<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="27" chg="U" itemnbr="1" key="UPS747MEL20070815103247" revdate="20090824" revnbr="7" sectnbr="81">
<title>Leading Edge Flaps Drives &ndash; (Pneumatic)</title>
<dispcond category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="8" nbrreq="7"
operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>One may be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>All electric drives are operative, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Takeoff obstacle clearance is not required upon retraction
of flaps from takeoff position.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815103248">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>LE SINGLE DRIVE</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>With one pneumatic drive inoperative, the caution
message FLAPS PRIMARY will be displayed during flap operation. The
FLAPS PRIMARY message indicates a temporary LE Flap disagreement as
a result of slower electrical actuation of the affected LE Flap panels.
At the completion of flap motion, with all panels in commanded position,
FLAPS PRIMARY will extinguish. Dispatch with FLAPS PRIMARY displayed,
or the status message LE MULT DRIVE, is prohibited. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>After Takeoff:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Leave flaps in takeoff position until obstacle clearance
is assured.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Retract flaps with the flap lever using normal procedures.
(The affected leading edge flaps will automatically be retracted electrically
at a slower rate than the pneumatic flaps).</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MEL20070815103249">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>If &ldquo;Obstacle Clearance Altitude (OCA)&rdquo;
is present on the AA Data for the departure runway, contact Flight
Control for alternate AA Data.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard near flap lever: "NUMBER ___ L (R) PNEU DR INOP". Enter
item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log. </para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815103250">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Check operation of the leading edge electric drives
as follows: </para>
<warning><para>ENSURE PERSONNEL AND EQUIPMENT ARE CLEAR OF ALL FLIGHT
CONTROL SURFACES.</para></warning>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>If all leading edge and trailing edge flaps are not
fully retracted, retract them using the flap lever.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>To inhibit trailing edge motion and leading edge pneumatic
motion, open the following circuit breakers on the P6 panel:</para>
<table frame="none">
<tgroup align="left" cols="1">
<colspec align="left" colname="col1" colwidth="281.69pt"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry align="left">
<para>PRI LE FLAP DR CONT GRP A (AC)</para>
<para>PRI LE FLAP DR CONT GRP B (AC)</para>
<para>TE FLAP ELEC CONT INBD</para>
<para>TE FLAP ELEC CONT OUTBD</para>
<para>PRI TE FLAP CONT DC</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<caution><para>DO NOT ELECTRICALLY EXTEND OR RETRACT THE FLAPS MORE
THAN ONE TIME IN 5 MINUTES. DAMAGE TO THE MOTOR CAN OCCUR IF THE MOTOR
BECOMES TOO HOT.</para></caution>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move the flap lever to 5:</para><para>The leading
edge flaps should remain stationary for approximately 15 seconds,
and then extend electrically. Verify that all leading edge flaps extend
by observing the EICAS non-normal (expanded) flap display and by observing
the flap panels.</para>
<note><para>The Caution message FLAPS DRIVE and the status messages
LE MULT DRIVE and TE FLAPS will remain displayed on EICAS following
this step.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move the flap lever to UP:</para><para>The leading
edge flaps should remain stationary for approximately 15 seconds,
and then retract electrically. Verify that all leading edge flaps
retract fully by observing the EICAS display and the flap panels.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the 5 circuit breakers opened in step B.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Press the ALT FLAPS arm switch. Press the arm switch
again and verify the messages FLAPS DRIVE, LE MULT DRIVE, and TE FLAPS
are extinguished. </para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>Status message LE MULT DRIVE may be latched by a single
pneumatically inoperative Flap Drive unit. If LE MULT DRIVE remains
displayed at conclusion of the maintenance procedure above, dispatch
may still be available by accomplishing the steps below and verifying
the message was latched by a single pneumatically inoperative Flap
drive unit.</para></note>
<para><emphasis role="bold">LE MULT DRIVE:</emphasis></para>
<note><para>The following procedure may be used to verify that LE
MULT DRIVE was latched by a single pneumatically inoperative Flap
drive unit. If LE MULT DRIVE remains annunciated at the conclusion
of the verification procedure, dispatch is not allowed.</para></note>
<warning><para>LEADING AND TRAILING EDGE FLAPS WILL OPERATE. ENSURE
THAT PERSONNEL AND EQUIPMENT ARE CLEAR OF ALL FLIGHT CONTROL SURFACES.</para>
</warning>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Apply power to Flap Control Units (FCUs).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Apply hydraulic and pneumatic power to the flaps.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move the flap lever to the &ldquo;UP&rdquo; detent
and wait until the flaps are fully retracted.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open and close the following circuit breakers located
on the P7 panel:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>7C10 FLT CONT ELEC 2L AC</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>7C11 FLT CONT ELEC 2L DC</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>7C12 FLT CONT ELEC 1L AC</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>7C13 FLT CONT ELEC 1L DC</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>7C14 FLT CONT ELEC 1R AC</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>7C15 FLT CONT ELEC 1R DC</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>7C16 FLT CONT ELEC 2R AC</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>7C17 FLT CONT ELEC 2R AC</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that all flap related EICAS messages and all
existing flap related CMC faults are no longer displayed.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move the flap lever to the &ldquo;5&rdquo; detent
and wait until the flaps fully extend. Affected leading edge flaps
will operate in the primary electric mode.</para>
<caution><para>DO NOT ELECTRICALLY EXTEND OR RETRACT THE FLAPS MORE
THAN ONE TIME IN 5 MINUTES. DAMAGE TO THE MOTOR CAN OCCUR IF THE MOTOR
BECOMES TOO HOT.</para></caution>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that LE MULT DRIVE is not displayed.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move the flap lever to the &ldquo;UP&rdquo; detent
and wait until the flaps fully retract. Affected leading edge flaps
will operate in the primary electric mode.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that LE MULT DRIVE is not displayed.</para>
<note><para>Dispatch is not allowed if LE MULT DRIVE was displayed
at any time after the circuit breakers were open and closed by Step
4 above.</para></note>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
