<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="27" chg="U" itemnbr="1" key="UPS747MEL20070815103226" revdate="20100707" revnbr="8" sectnbr="51">
<title>Flap Control Units (FCU)</title>
<dispcond category="C" downgrade="CATEGORY 2" maintenance="YES"
nbrins="3" nbrreq="2" operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>One may be inoperative or removed provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>It is verified that flap position RVDT sensors are
operative before each departure,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For PW and GE, if right FCU is inoperative or removed,
No. 1 demand pump is selected ON during takeoff and landing, and</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For PW and GE, if left FCU is inoperative or removed,
No. 4 demand pump is selected ON during takeoff and landing.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>If S/B 747-34-2349 or production equivalent has not been
incorporated and center FCU is inoperative or removed, MODE 4 of the
ground proximity warning system is considered inoperative.</para></note>
<note><para>S/B 747-34-2349 has been accomplished on UPS aircraft.</para>
</note>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815103227">
<caution><para>IF EICAS STATUS MESSAGE "FLAP SYS MONITOR" IS DISPLAYED,
A BLOCK TURN BACK IS REQUIRED.</para></caution>
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>FLAP CONTROL ___</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Triple channel autoland may not be available with
an inoperative or removed FCU. If triple channel autoland is not available,
status message NO LAND 3 will be displayed.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>When operating with an inoperative or removed FCU,
if the flight director is selected to the FCC associated with the
inoperative or removed FCU channel, the flight director will not be
displayed at speeds below 60 knots. Each FCC receives inputs from
the associated FCU channel.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>The FMC scratch pad message PERF/VNAV UNAVAILABLE
may be displayed. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>With an inoperative removed L or R FCU, the EICAS
advisory message >IDLE DISAGREE may be displayed in flight when selecting
idle thrust with flaps not in landing position and engine anti-ice
off.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If right FCU is inoperative or removed, select Demand
Pump 1 ON for takeoff and landing.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If left FCU is inoperative or removed, select Demand
Pump 4 ON for takeoff and landing.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>Display of the EICAS advisory message >IDLE DISAGREE on
the ground indicates failure of the ground minimum idle selection
system and MEL Item 73-21-1 should be used.</para></note>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MELCDL20080405101806">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Downgrade Aircraft Category Dispatch Status to CAT
2.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard below Captain&rsquo;s PFD on P-1-1 panel: "L (C or R)
FCU INOP". Enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815103228">
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Logbook at the prescribed intervals.
(Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<para>Deferral of this item requires downgrading to the status indicated
in the A/C STATUS DISPATCH column below.</para>
<table>
<tgroup align="center" cols="3">
<colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.00*"/>
<colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.04*"/>
<colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.96*"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">INOP POSITION</emphasis></para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">NUMBER INOP</emphasis></para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">A/C STATUS DISPATCH</emphasis></para>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<para>&ndash;</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>1</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>CAT 2</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<!--Per C.R.4265 Tim 10/28/09 for Rev 8-->
<note><para>The FCU's are interchangeable.</para></note>
<note><para>AD 2005-04-03 requires at least one operative FCU. Needs
to be P/N 285U0011-208 in accordance with<?Pub _newline?> SB 747-27A2386.</para>
</note>
<note><para>SB 747-27A2386 has been accomplished on all UPS aircraft.</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>If status message FLAP CONTROL__ is displayed:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Verify RVDT sensors are operative. This is accomplished
by ensuring status message FLAP SYS MONITOR is not displayed. If FLAP
SYS MONITOR is not displayed, no additional maintenance action is
required unless FCU interchange is elected due to an inoperative GPWS
MODE 4.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the center FCU is inoperative and interchange is
necessary for GPWS MODE 4 operation:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Open circuit breakers listed in Step 2. A. (2) below
and exchange either the left or right FCU with the center unit.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the previously opened circuit breakers.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>After interchange, EICAS Status Message FLAP CONTROL
__ will re-display to the inoperative FCU position.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If status message FLAP SYS MONITOR is displayed:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Verify the RVDT sensors are operative as follows:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Access CMC Existing Faults for >27 FLAP CONTROL. If
any of the following faults are present, all three FCUs detect an
RVDT fault. Dispatch is not allowed.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>LE_SWITCH FAIL</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>_RVDT FAIL</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Access CMC Existing Faults for >27 FLAP CONTROL. If
any of the following faults are present, either an FCU fault or an
FCU detected RVDT fault has occurred and the following procedure must
be accomplished to verify the RVDT sensors are operative:</para><para
>_RVDT &ndash; FCU-_INTERFACE FAIL </para>
<para>FLAP 26 VAC-_>FCU-_INTERFACE FAIL</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Open the following circuit breakers on the P7 panel.</para>
<table frame="none">
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec colname="col1" colsep="0" colwidth="176.16pt"/>
<colspec colname="col2" colsep="0" colwidth="176.16pt"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<para>7C10 FLT CONT ELEC 2L AC</para>
<para>7C12 FLT CONT ELEC 1L AC</para>
<para>7C14 FLT CONT ELEC 1R AC</para>
<para>7C16 FLT CONT ELEC 2R AC</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>7C11 FLT CONT ELEC 2L DC</para>
<para>7C13 FLT CONT ELEC 1L DC</para>
<para>7C15 FLT CONT ELEC 1R DC</para>
<para>7C17 FLT CONT ELEC 2R DC</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Label each FCU with LEFT, RIGHT and CENTER identification
marks so their original location remains known.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove the FCU that corresponds to the above reported
Interface Fail faults.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the above circuit breakers. Verify FLAP SYS
MONITOR status message does not appear within 30 seconds. If FLAP
SYS MONITOR message appears, dispatch is not allowed.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open the above circuit breakers and remove one of
the FCUs which is still installed. Install this FCU in the vacant
slot of the previously removed unit.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the above circuit breakers.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Wait a minimum of 30 seconds, if FLAP SYS MONITOR
message appears, an RVDT sensor fault is confirmed and dispatch is
not allowed</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If FLAP SYS MONITOR message does not appear, RVDT
sensors are verified to be operative. The removed FCU is classified
inoperative.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open the above circuit breakers and replace the two
operable FCUs in their original EE shelf slot. Do not replace the
inoperative FCU. </para>
<note><para>If the center FCU is inoperative and interchange is necessary
for GPWS MODE 4 operation, move either the left or right unit to the
removed center FCUs position at this time.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the above circuit breakers. Status message FLAP
CONTROL__ will re-display to the removed FCUs position.</para>
<caution><para>IF FLAP SYS MONITOR REMAINS DISPLAYED, DISPATCH IS
NOT ALLOWED. </para></caution>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
