<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="36" chg="U" itemnbr="1-2" key="UPS747MEL20070815105027" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="12">
<title>Precoolers &ndash; Alternate Method</title>
<dispcond category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="4" nbrreq="3"
operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>One may be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Associated ENGINE BLEED switch is selected OFF except
for engine start,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Aircraft is not operated in known or forecast icing
conditions, </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>L and R ISLN valves are open for takeoff, and when
flaps are operated,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Bleed systems on remaining engines are operative,</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Associated Engine Anti-Ice switch remains OFF,</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For PW &amp; GE, associated fan air valve is secured
in the intermediate open position, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Appropriate performance adjustments are applied.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>Aircraft may be dispatched with damage to the precooler
(including core damage) provided engine start is not precluded.</para>
</note>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815105028">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>For the associated engine, select Engine Bleed OFF
except for ground engine start and when bleed air is required for
inflight start. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>APU-TO-PACK TAKEOFF procedure is not permitted since
L and R ISLN Valves must remain open during takeoff.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>During takeoff and for all flap operations, ensure
that the L and R ISLN valve switches are in the open position. This
assures air is available for operation of the air-driven hydraulic
demand pump and LE flaps in the event of an adjacent engine shutdown.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Do not select associated engine Nacelle Anti-Ice Switch
ON. If icing conditions are inadvertently encountered, reducing thrust
on affected engine will minimize possible damage if ice is ingested.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MEL20070815105029">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Operations into known or forecast icing conditions
is prohibited. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Increase flight planning fuel by .3%.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Reduce performance limited takeoff and landing weight
by 2,200 lbs.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Reduce performance limited en route weight by 3,200
lbs.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>APU-TO-PACK TAKEOFF procedure is not permitted.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Install Placards below Captain's PFD on P-1-1 panel: "ENG____PRECOOLER
INOP" and "ENG____FAV INOP INTERMEDIATE OPEN". Enter items in Aircraft
Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815105030">
<title>PRECOOLERS</title>
<graphic chapnbr="36" chg="U" key="UPS747-400MELCDL20080807104850"
revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="12">
<sheet chg="U" gnbr="747-400_DMP_CH_36_Page_16"
key="UPS747-400MELCDL20080807105324" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5"
sheetnbr="001"></sheet>
</graphic>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Secure the associated Fan Air Valve (FAV) in the intermediate
open position as follows:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Open the left thrust reverser half (AMM 78-31-00/201).</para>
<note><para>The FAV is installed on the left side of the precooler.
 The valve is spring- loaded open and is controlled by the Fan Air
Temperature sensors.  It has a locking crank to permit the valve 
to be operated manually.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove the positioning screw from the FAV actuator
housing.  Remove and discard the O-ring.  Do not disconnect the retaining
cable from the positioning screw.  </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Turn the locking crank to the 45 degree position.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Install the positioning screw in the locking crank
until it is engaged with the switch bracket.  This will lock the valve
in the 45 degree position.  </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the thrust reverser half (AMM 78-31-00/201).</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
