<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="31" chg="U" itemnbr="1" key="UPS747MEL20070815104028" revdate="20090824" revnbr="7" sectnbr="61">
<title>EICAS Lower Integrated Display Unit (IDU)</title>
<dispcond category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="1" nbrreq="0"
operation="NO">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided it is verified that EICAS can be
switched to an alternate IDU (in case of en route failure of the EICAS
Upper IDU). </para>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815104029">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>IDS DU</para>
</note>
</operation>
<placard>
<para>Placard on lower EICAS display unit: "INOP". Enter item in Aircraft
Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815104030">
<para>This item allows dispatch only with the IDU located in the lower
EICAS position inoperative. The four EFIS IDU&rsquo;s and the upper
EICAS IDU must operate normally. However, all of the IDU&rsquo;s are
interchangeable. Therefore, if an IDU located in the upper EICAS position
or any one of the EFIS positions is inoperative (and no spares are
available), it can be swapped with the lower (operative) IDU. This
switches the inoperative IDU to the lower EICAS position to permit
dispatch per this MEL item.</para>
<note><para>CRT and LCD IDU's are completely interchangeable in the
UPPER and LOWER EICAS positions. The Captain's PF and ND IDU's or
the First Officer's PF and ND IDU's are to be maintained as a matched
set of either CRT or LCD IDU's. The mixing of both types of IDU on
the same side is not allowed. Mixing between the Captain's and First
Officer's sides is allowed but not preferred.</para></note>
<para>Use the following procedure to verify that EICAS display can
be switched to an alternate IDU:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Select INBD CRT switch on CAPT or F/O Display Transfer
Module to EICAS position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that EICAS is switch to CAPT or F/O inboard
IDU.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Return switch to NORM position.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
