<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="29" chg="U" itemnbr="2-1" key="UPS747MEL20070815103656" revdate="20090824" revnbr="7" sectnbr="11">
<title>Demand Hydraulic Pumps &ndash; No. 1 or No. 4 Demand Pump Systems</title>
<dispcond attr-rev="NO" category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="2"
nbrreq="1" operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>One may be inoperative deactivated provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>VMCG is increased by 5 kts.,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Takeoff performance must be in accordance with the
AOM/AA Data appendix for landing gear extended,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Takeoff obstacle clearance must be dependent upon
flaps remaining in the takeoff position, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Demand pumps 2 and 3 are operative.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815103657">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>HYD PRESS DEM ___</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Takeoff:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>With Demand Hydraulic Pumps No. 1 or No. 4 inoperative,
an engine failure at the same position will cause a hydraulic system
loss, preventing retraction of the related landing gear, and will
require secondary mode (electric) operation of trailing edge flaps.
Takeoff performance (including obstacle clearance) is thus based on
gear and flaps extended.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>After takeoff:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Retract gear with gear lever using normal procedures.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Retract flaps with the flap lever using normal procedures. </para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>At takeoff weights greater than 720,000 lbs, flaps
up maneuver speed (V<sub>ref</sub> +100 kt) may exceed 270 kts. Therefore,
ensure gear is retracted prior to selecting Flaps Up.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MEL20070815103658">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Apply restricted takeoff climb weights from the takeoff
climb limit weight, landing gear extended or brakes deactivated by
capping chart found in the AOM Chapter 5.1.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If Obstacle Clearance Altitude (OCA) is present on
the AA Data for the departure runway, contact Flight Control for alternate
AA Data. </para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard adjacent to associated #1 or #4 Demand pump switch:
"INOP". Enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815103659">
<title>DEMAND HYDRAULIC PUMPS</title>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Position affected HYD PUMPS DEMAND switch to OFF.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open and collar the associated P7 panel HYDR__DEMAND
circuit breaker.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the inoperative demand pump is an Air Driven Pump
(ADP), verify that the air shutoff valve is closed using one of the
following two methods:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Method 1:</emphasis></para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Pressurize the pneumatic manifold (AMM 36-00-00/201).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that no air is being exhausted from the ADP
exhaust louvers. If air is exhausting, continue with Method 2.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Method 2:</emphasis></para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Depressurize the pneumatic manifold (AMM 36-00-00/201).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open the RH trailing edge fairing door.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the shutoff valve is closed (actuator should
be fully extended).</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If both speed and shutoff valves are open, disconnect
at least one valve actuator from the valve shaft (leaving cranking
arm on shaft). Move valve shaft to the closed position and lockwire.
If shaft is loose or binds, indicating valve damage, close and lockwire
the other valve.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the RH trailing edge fairing door.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
