<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="28" chg="U" itemnbr="5-0-1" key="UPS747MEL20070815103618" revdate="20100707" revnbr="8" sectnbr="41">
<title>Reserve Tank Fuel Quantity Indicating Systems &ndash; Reserve
Tanks Fueled </title>
<dispcond category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="2" nbrreq="0"
operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative with reserve tanks 2 and 3 fueled provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Tank is emptied and serviced with a known quantity
of fuel, or measuring stick readings are taken to verify quantity
in tank with inoperative indicator after refueling,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>FMC is initialized with the known total fuel quantity,</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Engine fuel flow indication and FMC Calculated fuel
quantity are operative,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remaining individual tank quantity indications are
available, </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For Combi, if ballast fuel is carried, stabilizer
tank remains empty and CWT fuel in excess of ballast fuel may not
be carried.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>North Polar Route Restrictions.</para></note>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815103619">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>FUEL QTY SYS</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Total Fuel quantity indication may also be inoperative,
if so:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Total fuel quantity must be calculated and manually
initialized on the FMC PERF INIT page after engines have been started.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If it is necessary to jettison fuel:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Record the FUEL TO REMAIN quantity selected for the
jettison operation.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Wait two minutes after fuel jettison is complete and
then manually re-initialize the FMC with the total FUEL TO REMAIN
quantity recorded above.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Center tank override/jettison pumps should remain
OFF.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>In case of en route failure of the FMC calculated
total fuel quantity, flight crew must keep a fuel log for the remainder
of the flight. </para></numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>The PROGRESS page 1 display of Fuel quantity and actual
time of arrival (ATA) at the last waypoint prior to failure may be
used as a starting point. In some failure modes, PROGRESS page 2 FUEL
USED data may be available.</para></note>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPSB747-400MELCDL20090527112626">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>North Polar Routes prohibited.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard below Captain&rsquo;s PFD on P-1-1 panel: "RES TANK
#2 or #3 FUEL QTY IND INOP". Enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item
Log. </para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815103620">
<title>RESERVE TANK FUEL QUANTITY INDICATING SYSTEMS</title>
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Logbook at the prescribed intervals.
(Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<para>Verify the fuel quantity in the tank associated with the inoperative
quantity indication using one of the following methods:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Defuel the associated tank (AMM 28-26-00/201) and
service the tank with a known quantity of fuel (AMM 12-11-01/301).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Determine the fuel quantity using the associated tank&rsquo;s
measuring sticks (AMM 28-44-00/001).</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
