<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="52" chg="U" itemnbr="1-2" key="UPS747MEL20070815105433" revdate="20090824" revnbr="7" sectnbr="48">
<title>Main (Forward) Electronic Bay External Access Door Latch Pins</title>
<dispcond category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="4" nbrreq="3"
operation="YES" btb="NO">
<remarks>
<para>One may inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Integrity of remaining pins is verified,</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remaining pins are verified to be fully engaged, and</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verification procedures are repeated each time the
door is opened and closed.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815105434">
<note><para>If FWD EE BAY ACCESS DOOR is deferred as inoperative,
do not open unless maintenance procedures are followed.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Associated door indication may remain displayed.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Maintenance will verify the status of the affected
door(s) and communicate this to the flight crew as appropriate.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<placard>
<para>Placard below Captain&rsquo;s PFD on P-1-1 panel: "FWD EE BAY
ACCESS DOOR INOPERATIVE &ndash; DO NOT OPEN". Enter item in Aircraft
Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815105435">
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Log at the prescribed intervals.
(Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Verify integrity of closed door's remaining latch
pins (from inside the aircraft in the Main Electronic Bay):</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Remove the internal handle and door liner.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Visually confirm the integrity of the three remaining
latch pins.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Replace the door liner and internal handle.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Confirm that the door handle is in the latched position.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Visually confirm the three remaining latch pins are
fully engaged with their respective keeper fittings.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify the closed door's remaining pins are fully
engaged before departure:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Check that the exterior operating handle is stowed
flush with the door and is secured in the latched position by the
handle latch.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the door is flush with the fuselage skin.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the door is latched by pushing inward on
the door and verify that it does not move.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
