<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="32" chg="U" itemnbr="1" key="UPS747MEL20070815104311" revdate="20081208" revnbr="5a" sectnbr="53">
<title>BODY GEAR STEERING SYSTEM</title>
<dispcond attr-rev="NO" category="C" downgrade="" maintenance="YES"
nbrins="1" nbrreq="0" operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Body gear steering actuators are verified locked,
and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Body gear steering is deactivated.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815104312">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>BODY GR STRG SYS</para>
<para>> BODY GEAR STRG</para>
</note>
<note><para>On takeoff, assure all 4 engines are spooled evenly at
70% N1, prior to engaging TOGA.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>With the body gear steering deactivated or inoperative,
turning capability will be reduced. See the illustration in the AOM
chapter 3 for the depiction of the approximate minimum turning radius
using differential thrust in addition to nose wheel steering. As with
all turns, the cockpit must travel outside the centerline of the turn
to align the main path. The tip of the winglet describes the largest
arc while turning and determines the minimum obstruction clearance
path. All other portions of the aircraft structure are within this
arc. It should be noted from the turning radius illustration that
the wingtips are moved outboard about 11 feet, and travel 59 feet
in front of the cockpit.</para>
<caution><para>DO NOT ATTEMPT TO MAKE A TURN AWAY FROM AN OBSTACLE
WITHIN 11 FEET OF THE WINGTIP OR WITHIN 59 FEET OF THE COCKPIT.</para>
</caution>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Avoid sharp turns if possible, due to excessive tire
scrubbing. </para>
<caution><para>AVOID USE OF EXCESSIVE THRUST IN RAMP AREA DUE TO POSSIBLE
DAMAGE OR INJURY FROM JET WAKE.</para></caution>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Use modified GEAR LEVER WILL NOT MOVE UP Non-Normal
Procedure for Body Gear Steering deactivated in the AOM Chapter 2.1
and QRH.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MEL20070815104313">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Minimum 170 feet of pavement required for 180 degree
turn. </para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard Captain&rsquo;s PFD on P-1-1 panel: "BODY GEAR STRG
SYS INOP". Enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815104314">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Verify body Gear Steering actuators are locked.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Perform the body gear steering actuator lock switch
BITE test [AMM 32-53-16 procedure 3.F.15(a) through (i)]. Bit status
of "1" indicates actuators are locked. Bit status of "0" indicates
actuators may be unlocked or indication system may be inoperative
(refer to DMP <refint refid="UPS747MEL20070815104320" reftype="DMP"
>32-53-2</refint>). </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If any bit status indicates "0", verify actuator integrity
as follows:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Depressurize hydraulic system No. 1.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Tow aircraft (using normal towing procedures) as follows,
observing that no body gear steering actuator extension or separation
occurs: </para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Nose wheel left 45 degrees, move 50 feet, stop.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Nose wheel right 45 degrees, move 50 feet, stop.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Repressurize hydraulic system No. 1.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Deactivate Body Gear Steering using Procedure A and
if necessary, Procedure B (actuator leak) and/or Procedure C (control
module leak or pressure switch fault).</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>PROCEDURE A</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Remove nose gear torsion link apex pin and secure
upper torsion link so that it clears structure when turning.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open and collar the P7 panel BODY GR STRG ARM AC and
BODY GR STRG ARM DC circuit breakers.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Using tiller, steer left and right at least 25 degrees.
Verify that no body gear steering actuator extension occurs.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Reconnect nose gear torsion links.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>PROCEDURE B - Use when steering actuator(s) leaks
excessively. </para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Deactivate body gear steering using PROCEDURE A, then
disconnect the left and/or right steering hydraulic system as follows:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Disconnect the OUTBD and INBD CYL EXT (extend) hoses
and one RET (retract) hose from the associated body gear trunnion
swivel fittings. Cap the trunnion swivel fittings.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Loosen the B nuts on EXT and RET hoses on the associated
steering actuators. Drain the fluid from the hoses and re-tighten
the B nuts.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Cap and stow the disconnected hoses so they clear
the gear retraction swing.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Rotate the top disconnected swivel INBD EXT on the
right body gear, and/or the OUTBD EXT on the left body gear, toward
the nose of the aircraft to a horizontal position and secure there
with lockwire. This prevents possible interferences with closing of
slaved gear door.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Pressure check system.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>PROCEDURE C - Use when the hydraulic control module(s)
leak excessively or when a pressure switch indicates a fault.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Deactivate body gear steering using PROCEDURE A, then
disconnect the leaky hydraulic control module(s) as follows (disconnect
both modules for a pressure switch fault):</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Depressurize hydraulic system No. 1.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove the pressure supply lines (P1) to the control
module(s) (from the landing gear down LGD1 lines). Remove the return
lines (R1) that connect to the top of the control module(s). Cap disconnected
ports on tee line fittings. Stow tubes aboard aircraft.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Disconnect EXT and RET hoses at the associated steering
actuators and drain lines. Reconnect hoses.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Cap open ports on the control module(s).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Pressure check system.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Restore hydraulic system No. 1 pressure.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>The EICAS advisory message >BODY GEAR STRG may remain
displayed due to a pressure switch fault.</para></note>
<graphic chapnbr="32" chg="U" key="UPS747MEL20070815104315"
revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="53">
<sheet chg="U" gnbr="747-400_DMP_CH_32_Page_17"
key="UPS747MEL20070815104316" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5"></sheet>
</graphic>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
