<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="27" chg="U" itemnbr="2" key="UPS747MEL20070815103222" revdate="20100707" revnbr="8" sectnbr="48">
<title>Nose Gear Pressure Switch</title>
<dispcond attr-rev="NO" category="C" maintenance="NO" nbrins="1"
nbrreq="0" operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided stabilizer trim position is properly
set before each departure for the actual aircraft weight, center of
gravity and takeoff thrust setting.</para>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815103223">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>>STAB GREENBAND</para>
<para>STAB GREENBAND</para>
</note>
<!--Per C.R.4361 Tim and Fred J. 2/4/10 for Rev 8-->
<note><para>Steps 1, 2 and 3 are accomplished only at initial time
of Nose Gear Pressure Switch deferral and does not need to be accomplished
on subsequent flights with this item deferred.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>The Captain and Load Supervisor will confirm Automated
Scales were used for weighing the containers.</para>
<note><para>If Automated Scales were <emphasis role="underline">not</emphasis
> used, the aircraft load must be removed and reweighed.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>The Captain and Load Supervisor will visually verify
all Main Deck container numbers and positions match the Load Plan.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>The Captain and Load Supervisor will visually verify
the correct container numbers in door position of both forward and
aft lower cargo compartments.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<placard>
<para>Placard adjacent to Capt&rsquo;s and F/O&rsquo;s stabilizer
trim indicator: "NOSE GEAR PRESS SW INOP". Enter item in Aircraft
Deferred Item Log. </para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815103224">
<note><para>STAB GREENBAND status level (and advisory level) message
indicates that the nose gear pressure switch disagrees with the selected
greenband, or an invalid CG has been entered into the MCDU. Invalid
CG values are CG &lt; 8.5 or CG > 33.0. If the message is due to an
invalid CG input, the greenband indications on the Stabilizer Trim
Indicators will not be illuminated. If the message is due to disagreement
between the Nose Pressure Switch and the selected greenband, either
the NOSE UP or NOSE DOWN greenband indications will be illuminated.</para>
</note>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
