<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="32" chg="U" itemnbr="1-2" key="UPS747MEL20070815104159" revdate="20090824" revnbr="7" sectnbr="42">
<title>Anti-skid System Wheel Speed Transducers</title>
<dispcond attr-rev="NO" category="C" downgrade="CATEGORY 3a"
maintenance="YES" nbrins="16" nbrreq="14" operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>One transducer in a locked-wheel protection pair (fore &amp;
aft wheels) may be inoperative provided performance complies with
AOM/AA Data for two brakes deactivated.</para>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815104210">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>ANTI-SKID</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Locked wheel protection remains available.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Two Brakes Deactivated with tool penalty must be applied. </para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Observe performance limitations.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Maximum takeoff thrust must be used.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MEL20070815104211">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Downgrade Aircraft Category Dispatch Status to CAT
3a.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Compute V1 using the V1 correction, One or Two Brakes
Deactivated or One or Two Anti-Skid Channels Inoperative worksheet
in the AOM Chapter 5.1. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Apply takeoff performance runway weight corrections
from the Takeoff Runway Limit Weight Reduction, Brake(s) Deactivated
Using Special Tool Chart in the AOM Chapter 5.1.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Apply landing weight performance for 1 or 2 brakes
deactivated in the AA landing data.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Operations on cluttered or icy runways prohibited.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Use cutback runway is prohibited.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Install Placards as directed in DMP procedure. Enter item in
Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815104212">
<title>ANTI-SKID SYSTEM WHEEL SPEED TRANSDUCERS</title>
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Logbook at the prescribed intervals.
(Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<para>Deferral of this item requires downgrading to the status indicated
in the A/C STATUS DISPATCH column below.</para>
<table>
<tgroup align="center" cols="3">
<colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.00*"/>
<colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.05*"/>
<colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.95*"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">INOP POSITION</emphasis></para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">NUMBER INOP</emphasis></para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">A/C STATUS DISPATCH</emphasis></para>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<para>&ndash;</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>2</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>CAT 3a</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<para>Confirm antiskid faults, deactivate the associated wheel brakes
for ANTISKID TRANSDUCER X FAIL affecting fore-aft pair, and prior
to every flight review CMC messages when ANTISKID advisory message
is displayed.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Conduct a CMC Brake System Ground Test.</para>
<note><para>The ground set-up procedure may be simplified. The IRUs
do not need to be in NAV mode. (Ignore any IRS signal fault indications).
Hydraulic pressure is not required. Autobrake system does not need
to be armed.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Select 32 BRAKE CONTROL from the CMC GROUND TEST menu.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Execute the BRAKE SYSTEM BITE test. Record all antiskid
system configuration and input faults annunciated during the test.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Following the conclusion of the CMC Brake System Ground
Test, select the line-select key opposite the FAIL prompt on the CMC
and record the antiskid system fault. Continue to select the NEXT
PAGE key on the CMC as required and record the antiskid system faults.</para>
<note><para>When CMC message PARK BRK VLV NOT OPEN WHEN RELEASED or
NO PARK BRKE PWR is displayed, dispatch is not allowed (Brake Torque
Limiter is inoperative). This condition causes Status message PARK
BRK VALVE as well as ANTISKID OFF and BRAKE LIMITER Advisory messages. </para>
</note>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For ANTISKID TRANSDUCER X FAIL (fore-aft pair not
involved): </para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Notify AMC and flight crew that antiskid transducers
are inoperative, but affected wheel brakes remain operative.</para>
<note><para>Do not use BSCU message inhibit knobs.</para></note>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For ANTISKID TRANSDUCER X FAIL (fore-aft pair involved): </para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Use MEL item 32-41-1-X to deactivate the associated
wheel brakes.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
