<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="32" chg="U" itemnbr="1" key="UPS747MEL20070815104058" revdate="20090824" revnbr="7" sectnbr="30">
<title>Landing Gear Retracting System</title>
<dispcond category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="1" nbrreq="0"
operation="YES">
<remarks>
<para>May be partially or completely inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Inoperative components are properly secured, and</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Aircraft is operated in accordance with AOM gear down
appendix Chapter 5.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815104059">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Operate aircraft in accordance with Landing Gear Extended
performance.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If all landing gear is not to be left extended, use
of the following procedure will keep all wheel well doors closed.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Before retraction of operable landing gear, depressurize
the hydraulic system associated with the inoperative landing gear:
Body and Nose gear Hyd Sys #1, Wing gear Hyd Sys #4.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>After gear retraction, position gear lever OFF.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Repressurize the hydraulic system associated with
the inoperative landing gear.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MEL20070815104110">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Maximum operating speed is 270 KIAS/ 0.73 M.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Maximum takeoff weight is limited to 720,000 lbs.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Apply restricted takeoff climb weights from the Takeoff
Climb Limit Weight, Landing Gear Extended or Brake(s) Deactivated
By Capping Chart found in the AOM Chapter 5.1.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>RVSM operations prohibited.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Modify ATC flight plan suffix to the appropriate code.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Extended overwater operation prohibited.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If operations are conducted in known or forecasted
icing conditions during any part of the flight and if the destination
airport has a forecast landing temperature below 8&deg; C, reduce
the landing climb limit weight by 78,150 lbs.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard below Captain&rsquo;s PFD on P-1-1 panel: "___ LANDING
GEAR TO REMAIN EXTENDED". Enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log. </para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815104111">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Configure (pin) the landing gear to be left extended
for dispatch per AMM 32-00-00/201. The nose gear and/or main gear
(in symmetric wing and body pairs) may be left extended.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If all landing gear are to be left extended, in addition
to complying with the step above, the landing gear lever lock circuit
breaker (C01435) on the P7 panel must be pulled and collared.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Configure the Mach/airspeed warning system as required
by the applicable AOM appendix.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Access the Gear Down Dispatch Switch in the main electronic
equipment center.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove the safety wire from the switch guard.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Lift switch guard and place switch in the Gear Down
Dispatch position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close switch guard and install safety wire.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
