<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="36" chg="U" itemnbr="1" key="UPS747MEL20070815105041" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="16">
<title>APU Pneumatic Duct</title>
<dispcond category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="1" nbrreq="0"
operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative (leaking) provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>APU check valve is operative, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>IF APU is used for electrical power, the APU Bleed
Air Valve is deactivated closed.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815105042">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Observe the placard on the APU control module.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If APU is to be used for electrical power, use normal
procedures except leave the APU bleed switch OFF. APU bleed air will
not be available. </para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MEL20070815105043">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>APU is to be used for electrical power only.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Install Placard(s) as instructed per DMP. Enter items in Aircraft
Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815105044">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Confirm the operation of the forward APU check valve
and configure the valve for dispatch, if necessary:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Open wing and body gear doors.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the APU check valve has a valve bypass line installed,
remove the bypass line from the pneumatic duct.  On the downstream
side of the APU check valve only, seal the connection on the pneumatic
duct with a suitable cap.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Using an external air source, pressurize the pneumatic
manifold. </para>
<warning><para><emphasis role="bold">ENSURE THAT SYSTEMS AND CONTROLS
NOT INTENDED FOR OPERATION IN THIS CHECK ARE TURNED OFF TO PREVENT
INADVERTENT OPERATION OF EQUIPMENT AND LOSS OF DUCT PRESSURE.</emphasis
></para></warning>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check the pneumatic duct pressure normal for the air
source. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check the APU check valve for internal leaks by listening
near the valve.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove external air source.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the doors, if appropriate.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If leak is between the APU and the APU bleed air valve
or if the APU is not to be used for electrical power, install placard
on the cockpit APU control module: "DUCT LEAK - DO NOT USE APU".</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the leak is between the APU check valve and the
APU bleed air valve and the APU is to be used as a source of electrical
power, secure the APU bleed air valve closed:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Open wing and body gear doors.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>With the APU shut down and the APU bleed air valve
closed, check the valve position indicator in the closed position.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Disconnect the electrical connector from the APU bleed
air valve and stow securely.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the gear doors.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Install placard on the cockpit APU control module:
"APU TO BE USED FOR ELECTRICAL POWER ONLY".</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
