<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="36" chg="U" itemnbr="4" key="UPS747MEL20070815105052" revdate="20100707" revnbr="8" sectnbr="21">
<title>Engine Bleed Overpressure Switch</title>
<dispcond category="C" downgrade="CATEGORY 3a" maintenance="YES"
nbrins="4" nbrreq="3" operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>One may be inoperative deactivated provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Associated HPSOV is secured closed,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Associated Bleed switch remains OFF for takeoff,</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>A minimum of 70% N<sub>1</sub> (60% N<sub>1</sub> for
RR) is maintained at or above 10,000 ft. MSL, or 55% N<sub>1</sub
> is maintained below 10,000 ft. MSL on the associated engine while
in icing conditions,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Bleed systems on remaining engines are operative,
and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For GE, associated engine reverser is deactivated.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815105053">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>BLEED HP ENG ___</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>When nacelle Anti-Ice is on, maintain a minimum of
70% N<sub>1</sub> above 10,000 MSL and 55% below 10,000 MSL.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>With the HPSOV secured closed, it is normal for the
Pressure Regulating and Shutoff Valve (PRSOV) to close during engine
operation at idle or if engine power setting are unequal.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>The associated engine&rsquo;s thrust reverser is deactivated.
The REV amber indication and EICAS message ENG_REVERSER may be displayed
for the engine with reverser deactivated. Use symmetrical reverser
thrust as required. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Thrust Reverser deactivation will not affect control
of engine idle speed during flight but the affect engine will stay
in minimum idle on the ground. Therefore, EICAS message IDLE DISAGREE
may be annunciated during landing when the unaffected engines are
commanded to approach idle for reverser thrust operation.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>The associated Bleed Switch should be selected OFF
for takeoff and may be selected ON after flaps are UP.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MEL20070815105054">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Downgrade Aircraft Category Dispatch Status to CAT
3a.</para></numlitem>
<!--Per C.R.4299 David B. 12/16/2009 Rev 8-->
<numlitem><para>Takeoff on cluttered or icy runway is prohibited.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Install Placards below Captain's PFD on P-1-1 panel: "ENG____HPSOV
INOP CLOSED and ____ENG BLEED OVERPRESS SW INOP and ____TR INOP".
Enter items in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815105055">
<para>Deferral of this item requires downgrading to the status indicated
in the A/C STATUS DISPATCH column below.</para>
<table>
<tgroup align="center" cols="3">
<colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.00*"/>
<colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.00*"/>
<colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.00*"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">INOP POSITION</emphasis></para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">NUMBER INOP</emphasis></para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">A/C STATUS DISPATCH</emphasis></para>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<para>&ndash;</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>1</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>CAT 3a</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<para>Deactivate the associated Bleed switch.  This will prevent the
BLEED_ advisory message and the BLEED OVPRESS_ status message from
displaying due to activation from the Bleed switch.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Extend the leading edge flaps (AMM 27-81-00/201).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Gain access to the associated engine bleed air overpressure
switch (through access panel located on wing leading edge inboard
of the engine strut) and disconnect the electrical connector from
the switch.</para>
<note><para>The shorting wire in the following steps is UPS tool 747-36-002-101,
if available.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Fabricate a 3 to 4 inch shorting wire from 20 to 24
SWG type 6A wire (BMS 13-60 Type 1 or BMS 13-48 Type 10) and two 20
gauge pins (P/N BACC47CN1A). </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Connect sockets 2 and 5 with the fabricated shorting
wire and stow the connector securely using a bundle strap.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Secure the HPSOV CLOSED using the following procedures:</para>
<note><para>The HPSOV is located on the right side of the high pressure
compressor (HPC) case.  To deactivate the HPSOV, it is necessary to
remove the positioning screw in the valve actuator to release actuator
pressure.  The positioning screw is then installed in the switch actuating
lever to lock the valve in the CLOSED position.  It is necessary to
open the right thrust reverser half to gain access to the HPSOV.</para>
</note>
<graphic chapnbr="36" chg="U" key="UPS747-400MELCDL20080807105938"
revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="21">
<sheet chg="U" gnbr="747-400_DMP_CH_36_Page_12a"
key="UPS747-400MELCDL20080807110013" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5"
sheetnbr="001"></sheet>
</graphic>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Release the pressure in the pneumatic system (AMM
36-00-00/201). </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open the right thrust reverser half (AMM 78-31-00/201).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove the positioning screw from the actuator cap.
 Do not disconnect the retaining cable from the positioning screw.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Install the positioning screw in the switch actuating
lever to lock the HPSOV in the CLOSED position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the right thrust reverser half (AMM 78-31-00/201).</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Secure the Thrust Reverser</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Refer to MEL <refint refid="UPS747MEL20070815105646"
reftype="MEL">78-31-1-1</refint>.  Accomplish Maintenance (M) procedure
to deactivate the reverser in the forward thrust position.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
