<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="79" chg="U" itemnbr="1" key="UPS747MEL20070815105735" revdate="20090824" revnbr="7" sectnbr="31">
<title>Oil Quantity Indicating Systems</title>
<dispcond attr-rev="NO" category="B" maintenance="YES" nbrins="4"
nbrreq="3" operation="NO" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>One may be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>It is verified before each departure that the oil
tank is filled to the recommended capacity,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>There is no evidence above normal oil consumption
or leakage, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Associated oil temperature and pressure indications
are operative. </para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<placard>
<para>Placard below Captain&rsquo;s PFD on P-1-1 panel: "ENG ___ OIL
QTY IND INOP". Enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815105736">
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Logbook at the prescribed intervals.
(Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Fill associated engine oil tank (AMM 12-13- 03/301).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Inspect engine exterior, including fan stream area,
for evidence of oil leakage.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check associated engine's records to ensure oil consumption
is not "above normal."</para>
<note><para>Maintenance step 4 is not required provided the associated
engine has been run in the last three hours and no maintenance involving
the engine fuel and/or oil systems has been done since engine shutdown.</para>
</note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For GE CF6-80C2 Engines, if General Electric Service
Bulletin 72-648 has not been incorporated, prior to departure it is
recommended that the associated engine oil tank is inspected for the
presence of fuel as follows:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>At each oil tank servicing and daily inspection, and
following all engine ground runs associated with engine fuel or oil
system maintenance, inspect engine oil tank to detect fuel contamination
per 747-400 Maintenance Manual Subject 12-13-03. Presence of fuel
in oil is not a dispatchable condition. If the presence of fuel is
detected, accomplish Troubleshooting Procedure and Oil System Flushing
Procedure per 747-400 Maintenance Manual Subjects 79-00-00 and 12-22-03.
The following related Maintenance Manual Subjects can be referenced:
12-13-03/301 Engine - Oil Servicing 71-00-00/201 Power Plant - Maintenance
Practices 71-00-44/101 Power Plant - Troubleshooting 72-00-00/601
Engine - Inspection/Check 79-00-00/101 Oil Distribution - Fault Isolation.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<warning><para>WAIT A MINIMUM OF 5 MINUTES AFTER ENGINE SHUTDOWN BEFORE
REMOVING THE OIL TANK FILLER CAP TO ALLOW TANK PRESSURE TO BLEED OFF.
HOT OIL GUSHING FROM THE TANK COULD CAUSE SEVERE BURNS.</para></warning>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
