<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mfmatr PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<mfmatr chg="U" key="UPS747MEL20070815105755" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5">
<section chapnbr="00" chg="U" key="UPS747MEL20070815105756" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="01">
<title>GENERAL</title>
<textset chapnbr="00" chg="U" key="UPS747MEL20070815105757" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="01" textsetnbr="01">
<title>GENERAL</title>
<textgrp>
<title>GENERAL NOTES</title>
<para>This section contains illustrations and locations of missing
items approved by the 747-400 Aircraft Flight Manual (AFM) Appendix
Configuration Deviation List (CDL).</para>
</textgrp>
<textgrp>
<title>GENERAL LIMITATIONS</title>
<para>The associated limitations must be listed on a placard affixed
in the cockpit in clear view of the Pilot-in-Command and other appropriate
crew member(s). </para>
<para>Operation with those missing parts requiring a reduction of
V<sub>MO </sub> /M<sub>MO</sub>  is permitted only when the aircraft
has the appropriate alternate V<sub>MO</sub>  set prior to flight.</para>
<para>The Pilot-in-Command will be notified of each operation with
a missing part(s) by listing the missing part(s) in the flight or
dispatch release. </para>
<para>The operator will list in the aircraft Log an appropriate notation
covering the missing part(s) on each flight.</para>
<para>If an additional part is lost in flight, the aircraft may not
depart the airport at which it landed following this event until it
again complies with CDL limitations.  This, of course, does not preclude
the issuance of a ferry permit to allow the aircraft to be flown to
a point where the necessary repairs or replacements can be made.</para>
<para>No more than one part for any one sub-system may be missing
unless specifically designated combinations are indicated herein.
 Unless otherwise specified herein, parts from different sub-systems
may be missing.</para>
</textgrp>
<textgrp>
<title>WEIGHT REDUCTIONS</title>
<para>The performance decrements are cumulative.  Where performance
decrements are listed as negligible, no more than three negligible
items may be missing without taking further decrement.  For each missing
item more than three, reduce the takeoff, landing and en&nbsp;route
climb limits by 100 pounds.  For items listed as not requiring any
performance decrement, any accumulative number of items listed as
not requiring any performance decrement may be missing without any
further performance decrement.</para>
</textgrp>
<textgrp>
<title>EN&nbsp;ROUTE FUEL MILEAGE EFFECTS</title>
<para>The drag effects of many 747-400 CDL items are so small that
en&nbsp;route fuel mileage changes are negligible.  For items that
have en&nbsp;route climb weight decrements listed, increase the flight
planning fuel by 0.25% per 1000 lbs. of en&nbsp;route climb weight
decrement to account for the en&nbsp;route drag increase.</para>
</textgrp>
<graphic chapnbr="GEN" chg="U" key="UPS747MEL20070815105811"
revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="CDL">
<sheet chg="U" gnbr="747-400_CH_GEN_Page_2"
key="UPS747MEL20070815105812" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5"></sheet>
</graphic>
<graphic chapnbr="GEN" chg="U" key="UPS747MEL20070815105813"
revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="CDL">
<sheet chg="U" gnbr="747-400_CH_GEN_Page_3"
key="UPS747MEL20070815105814" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5"></sheet>
</graphic>
<graphic chapnbr="GEN" chg="U" key="UPS747MEL20070815105815"
revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="CDL">
<sheet chg="U" gnbr="747-400_CH_GEN_Page_4"
key="UPS747MEL20070815105816" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5"></sheet>
</graphic>
<graphic chapnbr="GEN" chg="U" key="UPS747MEL20070815105817"
revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="CDL">
<sheet chg="U" gnbr="747-400_CH_GEN_Page_5"
key="UPS747MEL20070815105818" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5"></sheet>
</graphic>
</textset>
</section>
</mfmatr>
