<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="31" chg="U" itemnbr="4-1" key="UPS747MEL20070815104037" revdate="20090824" revnbr="7" sectnbr="61">
<title>EICAS Status Messages</title>
<dispcond category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="462" nbrreq="0"
operation="YES">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided associated equipment is verified
to be operative. </para>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815104038">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Dispatch with inoperative (nuisance) Status level
message(s) is allowed by provisions of this MEL item. An inoperative
message is one which is displayed when there is no actual equipment
fault. Dispatch may be accomplished by verifying the equipment associated
with the inoperative EICAS Status Message is operative.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<placard>
<para>Placard "DISREGARD STATUS MESSAGE _____" below Captain&rsquo;s
PFD on P-1-1 panel. Enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815104039">
<note><para>Dispatch with inoperative (nuisance) Status level messages
is allowed by the provisions of this MEL item. An inoperative message
is one which is displayed when there is no actual equipment fault.
If such an EICAS message is suspected, dispatch may still be accomplished
by verifying the equipment associated with the inoperative EICAS Status
Message is operative, or by observing the Dispatch Deviation(s) for
the associated equipment, if available. The EICAS Cross Reference
List in Section 1 can be used to locate the appropriate MEL item for
possible dispatch.</para><para>Maintenance (M) procedures are presented
herein to verify normal operation of equipment for three nuisance
Status messages. These three messages do not have associated Operations
(O) procedures. The EICAS STATUS MESSAGE list and procedures associated
with them that follow are not intended to be all inclusive. </para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para><emphasis role="bold">FUEL SPAR VLV_ :</emphasis></para>
<note><para>The following procedure may be used to verify that the
Fuel Spar Valve is operative if dispatching with the EICAS status
message FUEL SPAR VLV_ displayed. </para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Check that all boost pumps and override/jettison pump
switches on the Fuel Control Panel are OFF.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that all fuel crossfeed valve switches on the
Fuel Control Panel are OFF.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that all FUEL CONTROL switches on the Control
Stand are set to CUTOFF.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that all Engine start switches on the P5 panel
are OFF. </para>
<warning><para>FAILURE TO OPEN APPLICABLE ENGINE IGNITION CIRCUIT
BREAKERS (CB&rsquo;S) PRIOR TO OPENING ENGINE FUEL CONT VALVE CB&rsquo;S
WILL RESULT IN AUTOMATIC FIRING OF IGNITER PLUGS IF/WHEN FLAPS ARE
OUT OF ZERO DETENT, NACELLE ANTI-ICE IS ON, CONTINUOUS IGNITION SWITCH
IS PULLED &ldquo;ON,&rdquo; OR ENGINE START SWITCH IS PULLED &ldquo;ON.&rdquo;
WHEN UNBURNED FUEL IS IN THE COMBUSTION CHAMBER, INTERNAL ENGINE OR
TAILPIPE FIRE MAY RESULT, CAUSING PERSONNEL INJURY OR ENGINE DAMAGE.</para>
</warning>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>On the P6 Main Power Panel, open the following CBs
and attach DO-NOT-CLOSE identifiers:</para>
<note><para>Do not proceed to Step 6 until Step 5 has been accomplished
in its entirety. </para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>6H2 FIRE EXTINGUISHER ENG 1 &amp; 3 A</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6H1 FIRE EXTINGUISHER ENG 1 &amp; 3 B</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6H4 FIRE EXTINGUISHER ENG 2 &amp; 4 A</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6H3 FIRE EXTINGUISHER ENG 2 &amp; 4 B</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6F1 IGN 1 ENG 1</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6F2 IGN 1 ENG 2</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6F3 IGN 1 ENG 3</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6F4 IGN 1 ENG 4</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6G19 STBY IGN ENG 1</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6G20 STBY IGN ENG 2</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6G21 STBY IGN ENG 3</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6G22 STBY IGN ENG 4</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6K19 IGN 2 ENG 1</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6K20 IGN 2 ENG 2</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6K21 IGN 2 ENG 3</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6K22 IGN 2 ENG 4</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>On the P6 Main Power Panel, open the following CBs
and attach DO-NOT-CLOSE identifiers:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>6L10 FUEL CONT VALVE ENG 1</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6L11 FUEL CONT VALVE ENG 2</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6L12 FUEL CONT VALVE ENG 3</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>6L13 FUEL CONT VALVE ENG 4</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Extend Wing Leading Edge Flaps for access to Spar
Valves. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Station an observer on an elevated platform near the
affected Spar Valve.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Observer visually verify that the Manual Override
Lever on the Spar Valve is in the CLOSED position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Set the associated FUEL CONTROL switch on the Aisle
Stand to RUN.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Observer visually verify that the Manual Override
Lever on the Spar Valve moves to the OPEN position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Pull the associated engine FIRE switch on the P5 Fire
Control Module.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Observer visually verify that the Manual Override
Lever on the Spar Valve moves to the CLOSED position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Reset the Fire switch.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Observer visually verify that the Manual Override
Lever on the Spar Valve moves to the OPEN position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Set the associated FUEL CONTROL switch on the Aisle
Stand to CUTOFF.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Observer visually verify that the Manual Override
Lever on the Spar Valve moves to the CLOSED position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Restore the aircraft to its required configuration.
Remove, DO-NOT-CLOSE identifiers and close all CBs opened in Step
E and Step F.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the Fuel Spar Valve positions were all positively
verified in the above Steps, the affected Spar Valve is operative
and the aircraft may be dispatched.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para><emphasis role="bold">LE MULT DRIVE:</emphasis></para>
<note><para>The following procedure may be used to verify that LE
MULT DRIVE was latched by a single pneumatically inoperative Flap
drive unit. If LE MULT DRIVE remains annunciated at the conclusion
of the verification procedure, dispatch is not allowed.</para></note>
<warning><para>LEADING AND TRAILING EDGE FLAPS WILL OPERATE. ENSURE
THAT PERSONNEL AND EQUIPMENT ARE CLEAR OF ALL FLIGHT CONTROL SURFACES.</para>
</warning>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Apply power to Flap Control Units (FCUs).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Apply hydraulic and pneumatic power to the flaps.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move the flap lever to the &ldquo;UP&rdquo; detent
and wait until the flaps are fully retracted.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open and close the following circuit breakers located
on the P7 panel:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>7C10 FLT CONT ELEC 2L AC</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>7C11 FLT CONT ELEC 2L DC</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>7C12 FLT CONT ELEC 1L AC</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>7C13 FLT CONT ELEC 1L DC</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>7C14 FLT CONT ELEC 1R AC</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>7C15 FLT CONT ELEC 1R DC</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>7C16 FLT CONT ELEC 2R AC</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>7C17 FLT CONT ELEC 2R DC</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that all flap related EICAS messages and all
existing flap related CMC faults are no longer displayed.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move the flap lever to the &ldquo;5&rdquo; detent
and wait until the flaps fully extend. Affected leading edge flaps
will operate in the primary electric mode.</para>
<caution><para>DO NOT ELECTRICALLY EXTEND OR RETRACT THE FLAPS MORE
THAN ONE TIME IN 5 MINUTES. DAMAGE TO THE MOTOR CAN OCCUR IF THE MOTOR
BECOMES TOO HOT.</para></caution>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that LE MULT DRIVE is not displayed.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move the flap lever to the &ldquo;UP&rdquo; detent
and wait until the flaps fully retract. Affected leading edge flaps
will operate in the primary electric mode.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that LE MULT DRIVE is not displayed.</para>
<note><para>Dispatch is not allowed if LE MULT DRIVE was displayed
at any time after the circuit breakers were open and closed by Step
2. D. above. Refer to MEL <refint refid="UPS747MEL20070815103247"
reftype="MEL"> 27-81-1</refint> if LE SINGLE DRIVE status level message
remains displayed.</para></note>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para><emphasis role="bold">ENG_ ESCV:</emphasis></para>
<note><para>GE SB 75-123 has been complied with on 570 thru 579. EEC
software configuration is later than 8.2N on 570 thru 579.</para></note>
<note><para>The following may be used to verify that the ESC Valves
have been removed if dispatching with the EICAS status message ENG
ESCV displayed on aircraft powered by GE engines only.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Verify that either GE Service Bulletin 75-123, or
the GE Block II Change or its production equivalent has been accomplished.
The Service Bulletin 75-123 permanently deactivates the ESC Valves
open. The GE Block II Change or its production equivalent permanently
removes ESC Valves from GE engines.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For aircraft with the ESC Valves permanently deactivated,
or permanently removed, or the production equivalent, the EICAS status
message ENG_ ESCV message may appear with EEC Software 8.2M and earlier
installed. No corrective action is necessary for the associated engine.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
