<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="21" chg="U" itemnbr="9-1" key="UPS747MEL20070815101859" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="61">
<title>Zone Trim Air Modulation Valves </title>
<dispcond category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="6" nbrreq="0"
operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided associated valve(s) is secured in
an appropriate position unless it is verified that associated zone
operation in MAN mode is normal.</para>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815101910">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may remain displayed:</para>
<para>ZONE TEMP</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>For operation with individual zone(s) trim air modulation
valve(s) secured in an appropriate position:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>For taxi, takeoff, climb, approach and landing, select
Trim Air switch OFF.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For cruise and descent, select Trim Air switch ON.
 During descent to avoid high temperature in affected Zone(s), select
Trim Air switch OFF before passing through Flight Level 150.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<placard>
<para>Placard as instructed in DMP Procedure<refint
refid="UPS747MEL20070815101911" reftype="DMP">  21-61-9-1</refint
>.  Enter item(s) in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815101911">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Ensure that the Zone Temperature Controller (ZTC)
is operative by performing the Chapter 21 TRIM SYSTEM Ground Test
using the CMC.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>If the test fails, perform the procedures below to
secure affected valve(s) in the appropriate position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the test passes, access the CMC Other Functions
page, and select SHOP FAULTS, 21 AIR CONDITIONING, and ZONE TEMP CONTROL.
If Shop Faults are present, an inoperative Zone Temperature Controller
(ZTC) will report one or more of the following faults:</para>
<table frame="none">
<tgroup align="left" cols="1">
<colspec align="left" colname="col1" colwidth="235.70pt"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<para>00 I/O BOARD A FAIL</para>
<para>00 MOTOR DRIVER BOARD A FAIL</para>
<para>00 I/O BOARD B FAIL</para>
<para>00 MOTOR DRIVER BOARD B FAIL</para>
<para>00 I/O BOARD C FAIL</para>
<para>00 MOTOR DRIVER BOARD C FAIL</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If one or both <emphasis role="bold">Board A</emphasis
> faults are reported, the ZTC has lost control to one or more of
zones Crew Rest (C/R), Fwd Main Deck, Aft Main Deck (Left and/or Right)
and/or Fwd Lower Lobe Cargo.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If one or both <emphasis role="bold">Board B</emphasis
> faults are report, the ZTC has lost control to one or more of zones
Flight Deck (F/D), Upper Deck *U/D), Fwd Lower Cargo, and/or Aft Lower
Lobe Cargo.</para>
<note><para>If one or both <emphasis role="bold">Board C</emphasis
> faults are report, the ZTC has lost control to one or more of the
following valves, dispatch may be available under other MEL items:</para>
<para>Flight Deck Flow Regulating Valve</para>
<para>FWD Lower Lobe Cargo Flow Regulating Valve</para>
<para>Aft Lower Lobe Cargo Flow Regulating Valve</para>
</note>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>To verify normal MAN mode operation for F/D, Fwd Main
Deck, Aft Main Deck (Left &amp; Right), Fwd Lower Lobe cargo and/or
Aft Lower Lobe Cargo zones, alternately select MAN W and MAN C on
the associated ZONE TEMP Selector on the ECS Maintenance Page that
the associated zone&rsquo;s trim air modulation valve responds as
commanded:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>If MAN mode is operative, placard associated Zone
Temp Selector(s) (P5 panel) "AUTO INOP &ndash; USE MANUAL".</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If MAN mode is inoperative for F/D, Fwd Main Deck
and/or Aft Main Deck zone(s), go to Step 3 below and secure associated
zone&rsquo;s trim air modulation valve(s) in the appropriate position.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>To secure an associated trim air modulation valve(s)
in the appropriate position:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Open the P6 panel ZONE TEMP CONT AC and ZONE TEMP
CONT DC circuit breakers.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Location of zone trim air modulation valve(s):</para>
<table frame="none">
<tgroup align="left" cols="1">
<colspec align="left" colname="col1" colwidth="506.71pt"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<para>Flight Deck: STA 1113, WL 340, LBL14 (Above Main Deck Ceiling)</para>
<para>Upper Deck: STA 1109, WL 340, LBL 13 (Above Main Deck Ceiling)</para>
<para>Crew Rest: STA 1111, WL 340, LBL 10 (Above Main Deck Ceiling)</para>
<para>Fwd Main Deck: STA 1253, WL 170, RBL 94 (RH Wheel Well)</para>
<para>Aft Main Deck: L STA 1253, WL 170, LBL 94 (LH Wheel Well)</para>
<para>Aft Main Deck: R STA 1253, WL 170, RBL 87 (RH Wheel Well)</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<note><para>The Aft Main Deck zone is equipped with two trim air modulation
valves (Left and Right). If control to only one of these valves fails,
it can be secured fully closed with minimal effect on the zone&rsquo;s
normal temperature control. Trim air modulation valves are identical
and interchangeable. A zone&rsquo;s temperature control with an inoperative
F/D, U/D, C/R, or Fwd Main Deck trim air mod valve can be enhanced
by interchanging with an operable Aft Main Deck trim air mod valve.</para>
</note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Disconnect, cap, and stow electrical connector from
affected valves.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Install an Allen wrench in the affected valve&rsquo;s
manual positioning shaft. Rotate the shaft until valves are in the
appropriate position as determined below and shown by the valve&rsquo;s
position indicator. Note that, except for full open and full closed,
there are no position markings on the indicators. Degree of rotation
must therefore be approximation between full open and full closed
&ndash; note that for each 1/4 turn of the Allen wrench, the valve
will move 10%.</para>
<table frame="none">
<tgroup align="center" cols="2">
<colspec colname="col1" colsep="0" colwidth="194.64pt"/>
<colspec colname="col2" colwidth="312.89pt"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry rowsep="0">
<para>Trim Air Mod Valve</para>
</entry>
<entry rowsep="0">
<para>Range of Appropriate Valve Position</para>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry rowsep="0">
<para>Flight Deck</para>
<para>Upper Deck</para>
<para>Crew Rest</para>
<para>Fwd Main Deck</para>
<para>Aft Main Deck</para>
</entry>
<entry rowsep="0">
<para>5% &ndash; 25% Open</para>
<para>20% &ndash; 30% Open</para>
<para>10% &ndash; 20% Open</para>
<para>0% &ndash; 40% Open</para>
<para>0% &ndash; 40% Open</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<para>For the Fwd Main Deck zone, a closed (0%) valve position will
result in a zone temperature that eventually stabilizes at approximately
40&deg;F (4&deg;C). A valve secured 40% open will result in a zone
temperature that eventually stabilizes at approximately 70&deg;F (21&deg;C).
This assumes cargo carried in the Fwd Main Deck is not heat generating.
For desired intermediate temperatures between 40&deg;F and 70&deg;F,
secure the valve at a position between 0% and 40%. For the Aft Main
Deck zone, there are two trim air mod valves. Both valves secured
closed with result in a zone temperature that eventually stabilizes
at approximately 40&deg;F (4&deg;C). With one valve secured closed
and the other valve secured 40% open, Aft Main Deck zone temperature
will eventually stabilize at approximately 70&deg;F (21&deg;C). This
assumes cargo carried in the Aft Main Deck is not heat generating.
For desired intermediate temperatures between 40&deg;F and 70&deg;F,
secure the valve at a position between 0% and 40%. F/D, U/D, and C/R
zone(s) trim air mod valve position selection must take into consideration
the fact that pack outlet air temperature is controlled to satisfy
the zone needing the coldest air supply temperature. If a relatively
cold zone temperature is selected for main deck or a lower lobe zone,
the F/D, U/D, and C/R zone(s) trim air mod valve position should be
positioned more open in their recommended range. (The opposite is
true if a relatively warm zone temperature is selected for a main
or lower lobe zone.)</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the P6 panel ZONE TEMP CONT AC and ZONE TEMP
CONT DC circuit breakers.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If Crew Rest and/or Upper Deck Zones are affected,
placard Cabin Temperature selector (located in Upper Deck) as appropriate
"CREW REST TEMP CONTROL INOP and/or UPPER DECK TEMP CONTROL INOP".</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the FLIGHT DECK TRIM MOD VALVE is secured in an
appropriate position, placard the FLT DECK TEMP selector on the Temperature
Control panel (P5) "FLT DECK TEMP CONTROL INOP".</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the FORWARD MAIN DECK TRIM MOD VALVE is secured
in an appropriate position, placard the FWD MAIN DECK TEMP selector
on the Temperature Control panel (P5) "INOP".</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the AFT MAIN DECK TRIM MOD VALVE is secured in
an appropriate position, placard the AFT MAIN DECK TEMP selector on
the Temperature Control panel (P5) "INOP".</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Advisory message TEMP ZONE may remain displayed and
the status message ZONE TEMP may remain displayed.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
