<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="28" chg="U" itemnbr="2-0-2" key="UPS747MEL20070815103325" revdate="20100707" revnbr="8" sectnbr="15">
<!--Per C.R.4347 Tim 1/21/10 for Rev 8-->
<effect chg="U" effrg="" efftext="N570UP-N577UP and N581UP-N583UP">
</effect>
<title>Hydro-mechanical Fuel Scavenge Systems</title>
<dispcond category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="2" nbrreq="0"
operation="NO" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided the first 3,000 lbs (1,360 kgs)
of center tank fuel is included as part of Zero Fuel Weight and is
considered unusable. </para>
<note><para>With two float valves inoperative open, it will be necessary
to deactivate the associated system(s).</para></note>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815103326">
<note><para>When the FUEL PRESS CTR L or R alerting messages are displayed
and related override/jettison pumps are turned off, 3,000 lbs. of
fuel will be trapped (unusable) in the center tank. Ensure load manifest
includes adjusted ZFW. </para></note>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MEL20070815103327">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>First 3,000 pounds of fuel is included as part of
the Zero Fuel Weight and is considered unusable. </para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard below Captain&rsquo;s PFD on P-1-1 panel: "SCAVENGE
PUMPS INOP". Enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MELCDL20080407114724">
<title>HYDRO-MECHANICAL FUEL SCAVENGE SYSTEM(S) DEACTIVATION</title>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Defuel the center tank using the pressure defueling
procedure and drain the remaining center tank fuel (approximately
125 gallons) through the sump drain (AMM 28-26-00/201).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Deactivate the Fuel Scavenge Systems.</para>
<note><para>Steps to remove the left fuel strainer are given. Steps
to remove the right fuel strainer are the same.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Go into the left wheel well for the wing landing gear.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Access the fuel strainer housing on the rear spar
of the center wing tank.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Position fluid absorbent pad (or something similar)
below the fuel strainer housing.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Put a suitable 5 gallon (19 Liters) fuel resistant
container below the fuel strainer housing.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>The quantity of fuel that can drain our of the fuel
strainer housing is 9.0 fl-oz.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Do these steps to remove the fuel strainer:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Remove the lockwire from the strainer cap.</para>
<warning><para>be prepared to re-install the cap on the fuel strainer
housing and contain any fuel that can spill. if the shut-off mechanism
for the strainer housing fails, fuel from the fuel-feed manifold can
drain through the strainer housing port. a fuel spill can cause a
fire or an explosion.</para></warning>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove the strainer cap and the washer (solid disk
inside the strainer cap).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove the fuel strainer.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove and discard the O-ring.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Do these steps to reassemble the fuel strainer housing:</para>
<note><para><emphasis role="bold">Do not install the fuel strainer
or washer. </emphasis> </para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Lubricate a new O-ring with petrolatum grease.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Install the O-ring on the strainer cap.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Install the strainer cap into the fuel strainer housing.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Torque the strainer cap to 250 in-lb. (28.2 Nm).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Lockwire the strainer cap to the housing body.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Do these steps again at the right fuel strainer housing.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Prepare the fuel strainers and washers for storage:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Inspect the fuel strainer and washer for damage.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Discard the component(s) if there is damage. Contact
AMC if any parts are damaged or discarded.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Clean the fuel strainer with water or air pressure
(90 psi (621kPa) maximum).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Identify, place parts in plastic bag and store the
fuel strainers and washers in PFM box.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Fuel Strainer Housing Leak Check:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Make sure that one main tank contains a minimum of
2500 lb. (1134 kg) of fuel (sufficient fuel to operate a fuel boost
pump).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Add or transfer fuel if it is necessary.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Set the crossfeed valve switches to the ON position.</para>
<warning><para>do not operate a fuel pump if the low pressure light
comes on and stays on. this condition can cause the ignition of the
fuel fumes in the fuel tank. a fire or an explosion can cause injuries
to personnel and damage to equipment.</para></warning>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>To operate any of the fuel pumps, you must be in the
flight compartment to continuously monitor the low pressure indication
and the fuel quantity in the fuel tank.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Immediately set the applicable fuel pump switch(es)
to the off position if the amber PRESS light comes on and stays on.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Do an external leak check for the fuel strainer cap:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Set one or more of the boost pump switches to the
ON position.</para>
<note><para>The boost pump switches are found on the fuel management
control module, M154.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Operate the boost pump(s) for 5 minutes.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Monitor the left and right fuel strainer housing for
leaks.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>After 5 minutes, set the boost pump(s) to the OFF
position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Set the crossfeed valves to the OFF position.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Visually examine the two strainer caps for leaks.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<caution><para>NO FUEL LEAKS ARE ALLOWED AT THE FUEL STRAINER HOUSINGS.</para>
</caution>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
