<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="52" chg="U" itemnbr="1-0-1" key="UPS747MEL20070815105444" revdate="20090824" revnbr="7" sectnbr="73">
<title>Door Indication</title>
<dispcond attr-rev="NO" category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="&ndash;"
nbrreq="0" operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided door(s) is verified closed and locked
by an alternate procedure.</para>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815105445">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may remain displayed:</para>
<para>DOOR AFT CARGO</para>
<para>DOOR FWD CARGO</para>
<para>DOOR SIDE CARGO</para>
<para>DOOR ENTRY ___</para>
</note>
<note><para>Lower E &amp; E and Bulk door indication will be EICAS
Advisory messages only and if either is inoperative will affect ACARS
report times.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Associated door indication may remain displayed.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Maintenance will verify the status of the affected
door(s) and communicate this to the flight crew as appropriate.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<placard>
<para>Placard near Primary EICAS Display: "DOOR_ INDICATION INOP".
Enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815105446">
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Log at the prescribed intervals.
(Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<note><para>Maintenance procedures are to be performed as the final
closing of an affected door(s) prior to takeoff.  The status of the
affected door(s) should be communicated to the flight crew as appropriate.</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Verify the affected door(s) is closed and locked as
follows: </para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Main Entry and Upper Deck Doors:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Check that the door is flush with the fuselage skin.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the exterior operating handle is stowed
flush with the door.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the interior operating handle is rotated
to the fully latched (closed) position.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Crew Compartment Overhead Door (Hatch):</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Open the door and check that the exterior handle is
stowed flush with the door and is secured in the latched position
by the handle latch. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close and latch the door.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Ensure that the latch pins properly engage the keeper
fittings on the body and that the arrow on the interior handle is
aligned with the LOCKED arrow on the  door lining.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Bulk Cargo Door:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Ensure the interior and exterior operating handles
are working in phase by pulling the exterior handle from its recess
in the door until it is fully extended.  Re-stow the handle.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the exterior operating handle is stowed
flush with the door.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the door is flush with the fuselage skin.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the door is latched by pushing inward on
the door and verify that it does not move.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Main/Center Electronics Equipment Access Door:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Ensure the interior and exterior operating handles
are working in phase by pulling the exterior handle from its recess
in the door until it is fully extended.  Re-stow the handle.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the exterior operating handle is stowed
flush with the door and is secured in the latched position by the
handle latch.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the door is flush with the fuselage skin.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the door is latched by pushing inward on
the door and verify that it does not move.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Forward and Aft Lower Lobe Cargo Doors:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Close and latch door per normal procedure.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the door is fully latched by observing,
through the door's view port, that the stripe on each rotary latch
cam is aligned with the arrow on the adjacent latch pin fitting.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Observe that the pressure relief doors are open prior
to closing the master latch lock handle.  Observe the pressure relief
doors closing while moving the master latch lock handle to the closed
position.</para>
<note><para>Do not force master latch lock handle closed.  Resistance
or interference indicates latch cams may not be in fully latched position. </para>
</note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the master latch lock handle and its trigger
are stowed flush with the door and that the pressure relief doors
are closed.  The top of a fully closed pressure relief door is approximately
one half inch inboard of the cargo door skin when plane is unpressurized.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Main Deck Cargo Door:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Close and latch door per normal procedure.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the door is fully latched by observing,
from inside the aircraft, that the rig pin slot in both the forward-most
and aft-most rotary latch cam is aligned with the rig pin hole in
the adjacent door structure. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Observe, from outside the aircraft, that the pressure
relief doors are open prior to closing the master latch lock handle.
 Observe the pressure relief doors closing while moving the master
latch lock handle to the closed position.</para>
<note><para>Do not force master latch lock handle closed.  Resistance
or interference indicates latch cams may not be in fully latched position. </para>
</note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the master latch lock handle and its trigger
are stowed flush with the door and that the pressure relief doors
are closed.  The top of a fully closed pressure relief door is approximately
one half inch inboard of the cargo door skin when the aircraft is
unpressurized.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
