<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="32" chg="U" itemnbr="2-2" key="UPS-757-MELSA2513600" revdate="20080924" revnbr="65" sectnbr="41">
<title>BRAKE SOURCE Indication System</title>
<dispcond btb="NO" category="B" maintenance="YES" nbrins="1" nbrreq="0"
operation="NO">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided: </para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>L and R hydraulic low SYS PRESS lights are operative,
and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Normal and alternate brake systems and brake accumulator
are verified to be operative. </para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<placard>
<para>Placard Brake Source light "LIGHT INOP" and enter item in Aircraft
Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757-MELJDM2510871">
<title>Brake Source Light</title>
<para>Check that normal and alternate hydraulic brake systems, and
brake accumulator are operational:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Check that landing gear ground lock pins are installed
(Ref. Maintenance Manual 32-00-20) and wheels are adequately chocked.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Release parking brakes by depressing both Captain's
or First Officer's brake pedals to the stops and releasing.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Pressurize the right hydraulic system with one electric
pump, observe R SYS PRESS light is not illuminated.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Depress and release both Captain's or First Officer's
brake pedals seven times minimum.  Brake pressure gauges should dip
momentarily (2000 to 2500 psi) at each brake application.</para>
<note><para>Both brake pedals should be depressed and released at
the same time.  Pause a minimum of five seconds after each brake application
before the next application.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that BRAKE PRESS pressure gauge on First Officer's
main instrument panel P3 indicates 2850 to 3500 psig.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Pressurize the left hydraulic system with one electric
pump, observe L SYS PRESS light is not illuminated.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Depressurize the right hydraulic system, observe R
SYS PRESS light illuminates.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Depress and release both Captain's or First Officer's
brake pedals seven times minimum.  Observe that brake pressure gauge
does not dip with brake application.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check the BRAKE PRESS pressure gauge on P3 panel indicates
2850 to 3500 psig.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Depressurize the left hydraulic system.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Depress and release both Captain's or First Officer's
brake pedals seven times minimum.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that BRAKE PRESS pressure gauge on P3 panel
indicates a lower value each time the brakes are applied.  Final pressure
should be about 1150 - 1500 psig.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Ensure brake accumulator is correctly serviced.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Restore aircraft to its required configuration.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
