<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="36" chg="U" itemnbr="2-1" key="UPS-757-MEL-00001109" revdate="20090814" revnbr="66" sectnbr="21">
<title>Pressure Regulating and Shutoff Valve Closed Position Indicating
System </title>
<dispcond btb="NO" category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="2" nbrreq="0"
operation="YES">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided associated valve is verified to
be operative once each flight day.</para>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS-757-MEL-00001110">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>If the left or right Pressure Regulating and Shutoff
Valve Position Switch is failed in the CLOSED position, the APU Shutoff
Valve will not be commanded closed when engine bleed is turned ON.
 Select APU or APU bleed OFF before turning the affected engine bleed
ON.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the left Pressure Regulating Shutoff Valve Position
Switch is failed Open, the APU Shutoff Valve will be commanded closed.
 APU bleed air for engine start will not be available.  Start the
left engine with ground air and cross-bleed start the right engine.
 The APU will not be available as a pneumatic source during the flight.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the right Pressure Regulating and Shutoff Valve
Position Switch is failed OPEN, the APU can be used to start the left
engine and bleed air from the left engine can be used to cross-bleed
start the right engine.  APU bleed air can be used as normal on the
left system only with the bleed air isolation switch off.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<placard>
<para>Placard near Bleed Air Supply Module (10259) on P5 panel "ENGINE
BLEED AIR OFF LIGHT(S) INOP" and enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item
Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757-MEL-00001111">
<para><emphasis role="bold">PRESSURE REGULATORY/SHUTOFF VALVE</emphasis
></para>
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Logbook at the prescribed intervals.
 (Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<para>Verify that PRSOV is operative:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Start engine on affected side.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Select APU or APU BLEED OFF.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Ensure the bleed air isolation valve is closed.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Select associated L/R BLEED AIR switch light to the
ON position. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Observe BLEED AIR DUCT PRESS on affected side is normal
(approximately 20 psi).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Select associated L/R BLEED AIR switch light to the
OFF position. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Observe BLEED AIR DUCT PRESS on affected side is 0.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
