<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="26" chg="U" itemnbr="1-2" key="UPS-757-MEL-00000640" revdate="20090814" revnbr="66" sectnbr="17">
<title>Wheel Well Fire Detection System</title>
<dispcond attr-rev="NO" btb="YES" category="C" maintenance="YES"
nbrins="1" nbrreq="0" operation="YES">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided an accepted procedure is used to
ensure brakes are cool before engine start.</para>
<note><para>Avoid possibility of retracting an overheated wheel by
leaving landing gear extended for ten minutes after takeoff. Pilots
must consider possibility of ice accumulation with landing gear extended
during winter operations.</para></note>
<note><para>In case of engine failure after V<sub>1</sub>, landing
gear should be retracted until takeoff obstacles are cleared.</para>
</note>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS-757-MEL-00000641">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>If not obstacle limited after takeoff, avoid the possibility
of retracting a wheel overheated by dragging brakes by leaving gear
extended for 10 minutes.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>In case of engine failure after V<sub>1,</sub> climb
performance is the prime consideration. Landing gear should be retracted
until at or above OCA then extended for a 10 minute cooling period.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>During winter operations from contaminated runways
retract the landing gear until reaching OCA, then extend the landing
gear for a 10 minute cooling period. </para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS-757-MEL-00000643">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Dispatch may be delayed to meet proviso.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Add 850 lbs. MEL fuel usage (10 minute gear down operation
for brake cooling).</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard adjacent to WHL WELL FIRE Light "INOP" and enter item
in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757-MEL-00000642">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Brakes must be checked for being cool (when hand can
be held on brake housings) immediately prior to starting engine.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Inform dispatch that flight planning may be affected.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If wheel well detection sensor(s) are failed closed,
the EICAS warning message WHEEL WELL FIRE and WHEEL WELL FIRE light
may be deactivated.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>To deactivate the EICAS warning message WHEEL WELL
FIRE and WHEEL WELL FIRE light, open and collar the W/W FIRE DET circuit
breaker on P11 panel.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Place additional placard next to the WHEEL WELL FIRE
light "WHEEL WELL FIRE LIGHT DEACTIVATED".</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>The center panel FIRE light and First Officer's panel
WHEEL WELL FIRE light will extinguish. The Fire light will continue
to be operative for engine fire and overheat detection. </para></note>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
