<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="24" chg="U" itemnbr="1" key="UPS-757-MEL-00000470" revdate="20100423" revnbr="68" sectnbr="00">
<title>Engine Generator Systems &ndash; Integrated Drive Generator,
Generator Control Breaker </title>
<dispcond btb="YES" category="B" maintenance="YES" nbrins="2" nbrreq="1"
operation="YES">
<remarks>
<para>Except for ER operations beyond 120 minutes, one may be inoperative
provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>APU generator is operative and is used to supply busses
of inoperative channel throughout flight,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>All generator control units, including APU, are operative,
and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For ER operations, Hydraulic Motor Generator (HMG)
is verified to be operative, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the APU has been operating for an extended period
of time in heavy falling or blowing snow, inspect inlet plenum before
departure to verify that accumulations of snow or ice are not present.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS-757-MEL-00000471">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Operate APU throughout flight.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Leave inoperative GEN CONT switch in the OFF position.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify APU generator is powering the busses of the
inoperative generator.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify both Bus Tie Switches are in the AUTO position
and the amber BUS OFF, APU GEN OFF, and UTILITY BUS OFF lights are
not illuminated. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>To ensure left engine bleed valve system is properly
configured for RR engines: If APU was used to start engines and remains
ON following engine start, cycle APU VALVE switch OFF, then ON after
starting the second engine.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>During heavy falling or blowing snow, visually inspect
the APU inlet plenum for snow and ice accumulation.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Land and Hold Short Operations (LAHSO) prohibited.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS-757-MEL-00000473">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Reduce Takeoff Climb Limit Weight by 500 lbs.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Reduce Landing Climb Limit Weight by 700 lbs.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Reduce Method 1 or 2 Terrain Clearance Weight by 1,500
lbs.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Add 370 lbs/hour MEL fuel usage for APU operation.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Land and Hold Short Operations (LAHSO) prohibited.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard affected L (R) GEN CONT switch (P5) "INOP - IDG DISCONNECTED"
and enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757-MEL-00000472">
<title>Engine Generator Systems</title>
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required for APU oil service
and when this item is inoperative must be documented in the Aircraft
Logbook at the prescribed intervals. (Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section
6.)</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Review logbook for evidence of APU high oil consumption.
If APU HOC is suspected, dispatch is not permitted.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check and service APU oil quantity before each departure.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that L, R and APU generator control units and
APU generator are operative.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Press BAT switch on P5 panel to ON (latched-in position)
(APU and external power off).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Press two BUS TIE switches to ISLN (out position).
Verify amber ISLN light in each switch is illuminated.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify two amber BUS OFF Lights are illuminated.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Press APU GEN CONT switch to OFF (out position). Verify
amber OFF light in switch is illuminated.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify amber OFF lights in the L and R GEN CONT switches
are illuminated, or L and R GEN OFF message is displayed.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that the APU GEN CONT switch is ON (latched-in
position). Verify OFF light in switch is extinguished.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Start APU. Wait 60 seconds.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify OFF light in APU GEN CONT switch remains extinguished. </para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify the following amber lights on P5 remain illuminated: </para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>ISLN lights in two BUS TIE switches;</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>OFF lights in L and R GEN CONT switches, or L and
R GEN OFF message is displayed.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Two BUS OFF lights.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Press two BUS TIE switches to AUTO.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify the following lights on P5 are not illuminated.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>ISLN lights in two BUS TIE switches;</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Two BUS OFF lights.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify amber OFF lights in L and R GEN CONT switches
remain illuminated.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Shutdown APU.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Press BAT switch to OFF.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If IDG was not disconnected previously, start the
affected engine.</para>
<caution><para>DISCONNECTING THE IDG WITH ENGINE BELOW IDLE SPEED
OR WITH THE ENGINE SHUT DOWN DOES NOT RESULT IN COMPLETE SEPARATION
OF THE DISCONNECT DOG TEETH. STARTING THE ENGINE WITHOUT RESETTING
THE DISCONNECT OR DISCONNECTING THE IDG WITH THE ENGINE BELOW IDLE
SPEED COULD RESULT IN DAMAGE TO DOG TEETH. </para><para>DO NOT ACTUATE
DISCONNECT SWITCH FOR LONGER THAN 3 SECONDS. ALLOW A MINIMUM OF 60
SECONDS BETWEEN ACTUATION PERIODS.</para>
</caution>
<caution><para>DO NOT OPERATE THE IDG FOR MORE THAN 50 HOURS IN THE
DISCONNECTED MODE WITHOUT RECONNECTION. FAILURE TO COMPLY WILL RESULT
IN THE NEED TO REMOVE THE IDG AND INSPECT THE IDG INPUT SHAFT BALL
BEARING ASSEMBLY FOR WEAR.</para></caution>
<!--Per E.O.#B757-2410-36598 and C.R.#4383 Bill Bombatch 3/10/10-->
<caution><para>IT IS ACCEPTABLE TO DISPATCH WITH LOW OR NO OIL IN
THE IDG IF THE IDG IS DISCONNECTED. IF DISPATCH IN THIS CONDITION,
THE IDG MUST BE CHANGED AS PART OF ANY MAINTENANCE ACTION TO CLEAR
THE DEFERRAL.</para></caution>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Momentarily press the affected GEN DRIVE DISC switch
no longer than 3 seconds and verify amber DRIVE light in affected
GEN DRIVE DISC switch and white FIELD off light in generator field
switch illuminates (A/C N401-426UP). </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify the following readings for the left (or right)
power channel on lower EICAS display:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>AC-V = 0 &plusmn; 5</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>FREQ = 0 &plusmn; 5</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify the following messages appear on EICAS:</para>
<note><para>If IDG Low Pressure switch is inoperative in the OPEN
mode, the associated DRIVE light will not illuminate and the associated
generator drive message will not be displayed, and therefore, item
C. (above) should be disregarded.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>L (or R) GEN OFF</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>L (or R) GEN DRIVE</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
