<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="34" chg="U" itemnbr="1-0-1" key="UPS-MEL-757-346101FDK" revdate="20091120" revnbr="67" sectnbr="61">
<title>Flight Management Computer Systems (FMCS) &ndash; One FMC/CDU
Inoperative</title>
<dispcond category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="2" nbrreq="1"
operation="YES">
<remarks>
<para>Except for ER operations, one may be inoperative provided en
route operations do not require its use.</para>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS-MEL-7573461101OPSFDK">
<para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">One FMC Inoperative </emphasis
></emphasis></para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Prior to dispatch, ensure the FMC instrument source
select switch associated with the failed FMC is selected to ALTN.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Position both pilot&rsquo;s HSI range selector to
the same range scale to obtain a map for the side with the inoperative
FMC.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para><emphasis role="underline">RIGHT FMC lNOP</emphasis
></para><para>LNAV and VNAV is available providing left or center
autopilot is used. </para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para><emphasis role="underline">LEFT FMC lNOP</emphasis
></para><para>LNAV and VNAV will arm but not capture unless 1) the
left flight director is turned OFF and the right flight director is
ON, or 2) the right autopilot is in Command.</para>
<table frame="none">
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec colname="col1" colsep="0" colwidth="75.55pt"/>
<colspec align="justify" colname="col2" colwidth="426.23pt"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<para>Procedure:</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>At 1,000 feet, select FL CH and position the command airspeed
cursor to the zero flap maneuvering speed. This puts the autothrottles
in the EPR mode and provides FL CH pitch guidance for flap retraction.
LNAV and VNAV may be used once the right autopilot is engaged.</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS-MEL-757-3461101LIMFDK">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Limited LNAV/VNAV availability to crew.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Two FMCs required for departing from domestic gateways
to Americas' Region destinations.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>For operations to Central, South American and Mexico destinations
ONLY, the flight may not depart outbound domestic gateways with inoperative
Flight Management Computer (FMC), but may continue series of flights
for repair interval specified in the Repair Int Category section.</para>
</note>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard affected Left or Right FMCS Control Display Unit (M76,
M77) "INOP" and enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS757MELCDL20080613083610">
<para>(Preferred to place inoperative FMC in the right FMC position.)</para>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
