<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="32" chg="U" itemnbr="5" key="UPS-757-MEL-SA32440501000" revdate="20080924" revnbr="65" sectnbr="44">
<title>BRAKE PRESS GAUGE (Flight Deck)</title>
<dispcond btb="NO" category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="1" nbrreq="0"
operation="NO">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Brake accumulator charge is verified normal once each
flight day, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Right low SYS PRESS light is operative.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<placard>
<para>Placard BRAKE PRESS gauge on First Officer&rsquo;s main panel
"GAUGE INOP" and enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757-MEL-SA324405325607">
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Logbook at the prescribed intervals.
(Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Check that landing gear ground lock pins are installed
and wheels are adequately chocked.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>With the right and left hydraulic systems depressurized,
check that the R SYS PRESS indicator light on P5 panel is illuminated.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Provide electrical power to hydraulic brake system.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Pressurize the right hydraulic system.  Verify that
the R SYS PRESS indicator light on P5 panel is extinguished.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Gain access to accumulator pressure gauge in the aft
hydraulic bay (197KL, in the wing fairing, see illustration).</para>
<warning><para>DOOR LOCKS MUST BE PROPERLY INSTALLED BEFORE GAINING
ACCESS TO PARKING BRAKE ACCUMULATOR (REF. MAINTENANCE MANUAL 32-00-15).
 RAPID ACTION OF DOORS MAY CAUSE INJURY OR DAMAGE, IF LOCKS ARE NOT
PROPERLY INSTALLED. </para></warning>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the pressure gauge indicates 2850 to 3500
psig. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Turn off the hydraulic pump.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Discharge hydraulic pressure from parking brake accumulator
by use of either the Captain's or the First Officer's brake pedals.
 Full depress and release forth pedals at the same time:  seven times
minimum.  Verify R SYS PRESS indicator light illuminated.</para>
<note><para>Pause a minimum of 5 seconds after each brake application
before next application.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify accumulator pressure is 1150 to 1500 psig.</para>
<note><para>On a day cooler than 20&ordm;C, proper accumulator pressure
is below 1300 psi.  Correct pressure as a function of ambient temperature
is identified on a placard near the charge valve.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Restore aircraft to its required configuration.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<graphic chapnbr="32" chg="U" confnbr="5" key="UPS757DMPFIG3216"
revdate="20080924" revnbr="65" sectnbr="44">
<title>BRAKE PRESSURE GAUGE</title>
<sheet chg="U" gnbr="DMP_CH_32_Page_16" key="UPSDMP_CH_32_Page_16"
revdate="20080924" revnbr="65"></sheet>
</graphic>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
