<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="28" chg="U" itemnbr="1-1" key="UPS-757-MEL-00000826" revdate="20091120" revnbr="67" sectnbr="41">
<title>Fuel Tank Quantity Indication Systems (Flight Deck) &ndash;
Main Tank Indicators  </title>
<dispcond btb="YES" category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="2" nbrreq="1"
operation="YES">
<remarks>
<para>Except for ER operations, one may be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Fuel quantity in associated tank is verified by an
alternate procedure,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For non-PIP and non-Pegasus FMCs, both EICAS computers
are operative,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Fuel flow indications are operative,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>FMC FUEL is initialized with known total fuel quantity, </para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Procedures to identify and contain an inflight engine
fuel leak are used,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>All main tank boost pumps are operative,</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Fuel pump low PRESS lights for associated tank are
operative, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For Pegasus FMCs with Operational Program Software
part number 3418-HNP-02C-08 or earlier, Thrust Management System is
operative.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>FUEL CONFIG advisory message for lateral imbalance may
be inhibited. </para></note>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS-757-MEL-00000827">
<para><emphasis role="underline">PREFLIGHT PLANNING :</emphasis></para>
<para>Review Inflight Engine Fuel Leak procedures in the QRH and the
Non-normal section of the AOM.</para>
<para><emphasis role="underline">OPERATIONS :</emphasis></para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Operate the flight with the fuel crossfeed valve(s)
closed. </para>
<note><para>FUEL CONFIG advisory message or light will not display
for a fuel imbalance condition when left or right fuel quantity indicator
is inoperative.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Compare FMC calculated fuel and the operative gauge
(times 2) with the flight plan fuel remaining at each waypoint or
fix for which predicted fuel is available.  The first non-visual clue
that a significant fuel leak has occurred will be either:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Excessive engine fuel flow or rapidly reducing fuel
quantity indication (if the leak resides on the side associated with
an operating fuel quantity indication),</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>An excessive lateral trim requirement, or</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>An engine flame-out.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remain alert for any such indication and at the first
detection of an engine fuel leak the crew must shut down the affected
engine (flight conditions permitting) to stop the leak and retain
fuel.  After shut down the fuel remaining in any tank may be used
for the operating engine.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Prior to each engine start, confirm that on the FMC
Performance Initialization Page FUEL is initialized with the known
total fuel quantity.  If boxes appear, or the displayed quantity is
incorrect, the quantity must be entered manually.</para>
<note><para>If fuel quantity is entered manually, MANUAL appears following
the entry.  The TOTALIZER display on PROGRESS page 2 is blanked and
fuel quantity from the Fuel Quantity Processor Unit is ignored for
the remainder of the flight.  The FMC now uses calculated fuel quantity.</para>
</note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Prior to each engine start, confirm that fuel flow
system inputs are valid on the FMC SENSOR STATUS Page 1 (LEFT AND
RIGHT FUEL FLO). </para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Select maintenance prompt on INIT/REF Page.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Select sensors prompt.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify left and right fuel flow inputs are okay.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Aileron trim indication on the control wheel can be
used to determine if a fuel imbalance condition exists.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>(Optional) Prior to each engine shut down, record
FMC CALCULATED FUEL QTY.  For flights not requiring additional fuel,
this value may be used as a means of determining total fuel quantity.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>In case of en route failure of the FMC calculated
total fuel quantity, flight crew should keep a fuel log for the remainder
of the flight. </para></numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>The PROGRESS page 1 display of FUEL quantity and ATA at
the last waypoint prior to failure may be used as starting point.
 In some failure modes, PROGRESS page 2 FUEL USED data may be available.</para>
</note>
</operation>
<placard>
<para>Placard affected Fuel Quantity Indication "INOP" and enter item
in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757-MEL-00000828">
<title>Fuel Tank Quantity Indication Systems (Flight Deck)</title>
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Logbook at the prescribed intervals.
(Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<para>Determine the fuel quantity by one of the following means:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Check the applicable tank fuel quantity indicator
on the fueling control panel (P28). If it is operating normally, it
may be used as the means of determining the quantity in the tank with
the inoperative gauge. If it is not operating, placard it inoperative
and notify the fuel crew that the automatic fueling shutoff function
may be inoperative.</para><para><emphasis role="bold">OR</emphasis
></para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Measuring Stick Method</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Determine fuel quantity by referring to UPS Fueling
Manual B757 section.</para><para><emphasis role="bold">OR</emphasis
></para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Level aircraft laterally and determine the fuel quantity
in the affected tank by comparing corresponding Fuel Measuring Sticks.
This can be accomplished by comparing fuel stick readings while tanks
are being fueled. When main tank with operative gauge has been fueled
to the desired fuel quantity, stop fueling of the affected tank. Adjust
fuel load until fuel stick readings between tanks agree.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<para><emphasis role="bold">OR</emphasis></para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Service the affected tank using one of the following
procedures: </para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Use tank-to-tank transfer as follows:</para>
<caution><para>OBSERVE FUEL QUANTITY LIMITS FOR EACH TANK WHEN TRANSFERRING
FUEL FROM ONE TANK TO THE OTHER.</para></caution>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Determine that the tank or tanks to which the fuel
is to be transferred (tank(s) with operative quantity gauge(s)) have
sufficient capacity to receive the fuel from the tank with the inoperative
gauge.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open the defueling valve.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open the fueling valve for tank(s) to receive the
fuel.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Turn on boost pump(s) in tank being defueled (tank
with inoperative quantity gauge).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>After the tank is emptied, re-transfer into it the
desired quantity of fuel (using the operative gauge of the supplying
tank for measuring), or pump in a known quantity from the refueling
truck using the truck meter. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Fuel the remaining tanks to the desired quantity in
the normal manner.</para><para><emphasis role="bold">OR</emphasis
></para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Empty, then refill the tank with a known quantity
of fuel, using fuel truck meter or from another tank with an operative
fuel quantity indicator.</para><para><emphasis role="bold">OR</emphasis
></para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For a flight not requiring additional fuel, the FMC
CALCULATED fuel quantity recorded at the end of the previous flight
may be used to determine total fuel quantity. The fuel quantity in
the affected tank may then be determined by subtracting the fuel in
the tank(s) with normally operating gauge(s) from the FMC CALCULATED
fuel quantity recorded.</para>
<note><para>With a fuel tank quantity gauge inoperative, the total
fuel quantity indication (MEL <refint refid="UPS-757-MEL-00000849"
reftype="MEL">28-41-7-1</refint> and <refint
refid="UPS757MELCDL20080604151459" reftype="MEL">28-41-7-2</refint
>) may be in error.</para></note>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
