<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="21" chg="U" itemnbr="13" key="UPS-757-MEL-00000185" revdate="20080924" revnbr="65" sectnbr="58">
<title>Equipment Cooling Airflow Detection System </title>
<dispcond btb="YES" category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="1" nbrreq="0"
operation="NO">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided equipment cooling airflow is verified
to be operative before each flight.</para>
</remarks>
<placard>
<para>Placard near EICAS "EQUIPMENT COOLING AIRFLOW DETECTION SYSTEM
INOP" and enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757-MEL-00000186">
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Logbook at the prescribed intervals.
(Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<para>When the equipment cooling airflow detection system is inoperative,
indicated by EICAS status messages "EQPT CLG FLOW", "EQPT CLG SENSOR"
or "EQPT CLG TEST" being displayed, use the following procedures to
verify equipment cooling airflow is normal. If normal equipment cooling
cannot be established, then the aircraft cannot be dispatched. </para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>EQPT CLG FLOW displayed:</para><para>Remove and stow
the connector from the respective equipment cooling sensor associated
with the displayed EICAS message and perform the following procedures
based on the associated EICAS maintenance message.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>FWD EQ SUP FLOW (M) (Sensor TS5292) &ndash; Remove
the right HSI per maintenance manual instructions and verify that
airflow can be felt with a hand located against the first officers
control column. Reinstall the HSI per maintenance manual instructions.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>FWD EQ EXH FLOW (M) (Sensor TS5293) &ndash; Verify
that air is exhausted at the equipment cooling overboard exhaust valve.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>AFT EQ FLOW (M) &ndash; Remove a unit, per maintenance
manual instruction, from the E6 rack and verify that airflow can be
felt with a hand placed against the bottom of the next higher shelf.
Reinstall the unit per maintenance manual instructions.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>EQPT CLG SENSOR displayed:</para><para>Perform the
following procedures based on the associated EICAS Maintenance message.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>FWD EQ SUP SNSR (M) &ndash; Perform check procedure
identified in 1.a.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>FWD EQ EXH SNSR (M) &ndash; Perform check procedure
identified in 1.b.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>AFT EQ SUP SNSR (M) &ndash; Perform check procedure
identified in 1.c.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>EQPT CLG TEST displayed:</para><para>Perform check
procedures identified in 1.a., 1.b., and 1.c. If only EQPT CLG TEST
is displayed, sensor connectors do not need to be disconnected.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
