<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="27" chg="U" itemnbr="2" key="UPS-757-MEL-00000737" revdate="20080924" revnbr="65" sectnbr="41">
<title>Horizontal Stabilizer Primary Trim Channels</title>
<dispcond btb="NO" category="C" downgrade="CATEGORY 1/2/3a"
maintenance="YES" nbrins="2" nbrreq="1" operation="YES">
<remarks>
<para>One may be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Horizontal stabilizer trim is operative by manual
trim levers, (Electrical Alternate Trim Switches),</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Approach minimums do not require use of three autopilots,
and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>No arm or control valves are failed in energized position. </para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<para><emphasis role="bold">CATEGORY 3b</emphasis></para>
<para>Installed: 2</para>
<para>Required: 2</para>
<para>May be inoperative.</para>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS-757-MEL-00000738">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>STAB TRIM Light may illuminate.  If light illuminates,
trimming will be reduced to half the signaled rate.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>DMP procedures confirms full trim rate is available from
the alternate trim system prior to dispatch.</para></note>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS-757-MEL-00000SA001">
<para>Downgrade aircraft category dispatch status to CAT 3a.</para>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>If LEFT Stabilizer Trim Control Module is inoperative, placard
the Left Autopilot Channel "PITCH FUNCTION UNAVAILABLE" and enter
item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
<para>If RIGHT Stabilizer Trim Control Module is inoperative, placard
the Right Autopilot Channel "PITCH FUNCTION UNAVAILABLE" and enter
item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log. </para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757-MEL-00000739">
<para>Deferral of this item requires downgrading to the status indicated
in the A/C STATUS DISPATCH column below.</para>
<table>
<tgroup align="center" cols="3">
<colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.98*"/>
<colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.98*"/>
<colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.03*"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<para>INOP POSITION</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>NUMBER INOP</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>A/C STATUS DISPATCH</para>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<para>&ndash;</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>1</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>CAT 3a</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Check that horizontal stabilizer is operative in one
primary trim channel (left or right).</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Provide electrical power (Ref. Maintenance Manual
24-22-00). </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Provide right and center hydraulic systems power (Ref.
Maintenance Manual 29-11-00).</para>
<warning><para>KEEP ALL PERSONNEL AND EQUIPMENT CLEAR OF CONTROL SURFACES,
CABLES AND LANDING GEAR AREAS.  PRESSURIZATION OF A HYDRAULIC SYSTEM
CAN MOVE CONTROL SURFACES, CABLES, LANDING GEAR AND LANDING GEAR DOORS.
 MOVEMENT OF CONTROL SURFACES, CABLES, LANDING GEAR AND LANDING GEAR
DOORS CAN CAUSE INJURY TO PERSONS AND DAMAGE TO EQUIPMENT.</para>
</warning>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that STAB TRIM SHUTOFF-R (11C13) and STAB TRIM
SHUTOFF-L (11C12) circuit breakers (P11) are closed.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the STAB TRIM CONT-L circuit breaker (11H11)
(P11) is closed.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the stabilizer is positioned between 6
and 12 units of trim.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the R and C FLT CONTROL SHUTOFF switches
on the right side panel (P61) are ON.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Place the RIGHT STAB TRIM CUTOUT SWITCH on control
stand to NORM.  Place the CENTER STAB TRIM CUTOUT SWITCH to CUTOUT.
 The right trim channel is now isolated.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move either Captain's or First Officer's stabilizer
trim control wheel switches up then down.  If the stabilizer does
not move in BOTH directions, the right primary trim channel is inoperative.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Place the RIGHT STAB TRIM CUTOUT SWITCH to CUTOUT.
 Place the CENTER STAB TRIM CUTOUT SWITCH to NORM.  The left trim
channel is now isolated.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move either the Captain's or First Officer's stabilizer
trim control wheel switches up and then down.  If the stabilizer does
not move in both directions, the left primary trim channel is inoperative.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>One primary trim channel (left or right) must be operative
in order to dispatch.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that no arm or control valve is failed in the
energized position.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Check that the stabilizer is positioned between 6
and 12 units of trim.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Place the RIGHT STAB TRIM CUTOUT SWITCH to NORM. 
Verify that the CENTER STAB TRIM CUTOUT SWITCH is also in the NORM
position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move the left STABILIZER TRIM LEVER (ALTERNATE STABILIZER
TRIM SWITCH) on the control stand in both the aircraft nose up and
aircraft nose down directions.  Verify that the stabilizer does not
move.  If the stabilizer does move, an arm or control valve is failed
in the energized position and dispatch is not allowed until repairs
are made.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move the right STABILIZER TRIM LEVER (ALTERNATE STABILIZER
TRIM SWITCH) on the control stand in both the aircraft nose up and
aircraft nose down directions.  Verify that the stabilizer does not
move.  If the stabilizer does move, and arm or control valve is failed
in the energized position and dispatch is not allowed until repairs
are made.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the horizontal stabilizer trim operates
with the STABILIZER TRIM LEVERS (ALTERNATE STABILIZER TRIM SWITCHES).</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Place the CENTER STAB TRIM CUTOUT SWITCH to CUTOUT.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move both STABILIZER TRIM LEVERS (ALTERNATE STABILIZER
TRIM SWITCHES) on control stand in both the aircraft nose up and aircraft
nose down directions, and verify that the stabilizer moves in both
directions. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Place the CENTER STAB TRIM CUTOUT SWITCH to NORM.
 Place the RIGHT STAB TRIM CUTOUT SWITCH to CUTOUT.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move both STABILIZER TRIM LEVERS (ALTERNATE STABILIZER
TRIM SWITCHES) on control stand in both the aircraft nose up and aircraft
nose down directions and verify that the stabilizer moves in both
directions.</para>
<note><para>Horizontal stabilizer trim must operate with the stabilizer
trim levers (alternate stabilizer trim switches) in order to dispatch.</para>
</note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Place the RIGHT STAB TRIM CUTOUT SWITCH to NORM.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove electrical and hydraulic power.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
