<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="28" chg="U" itemnbr="1" key="UPS-757-MEL-00000779" revdate="20090814" revnbr="66" sectnbr="21">
<title>Pressure Fueling System </title>
<dispcond btb="NO" category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="1" nbrreq="0"
operation="NO">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided alternate procedures are established
and used.</para>
<note><para>See Maintenance Procedures Section for alternate procedure.</para>
</note>
</remarks>
<placard>
<para>Placard near EICAS "PRESSURE FUELING SYSTEM INOP" and enter
item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757-MEL-00000780">
<note><para>Any fill valve that is operative may be used.</para></note>
<note><para>Auto overfill system may be overridden with overfill reset
switch to fuel aircraft.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Utilize individual components of pressure fuel system
which is operative.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the entire system is inoperative, fuel aircraft
from above the wing in accordance with AMM procedures.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the automatic function of the fuel shutoff valve(s)
is inoperative, then utilize the manual electric function of the same
valve(s) in accordance with AMM procedures.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>When the pressure fueling system is inoperative, gravity
fueling of the main fuel tanks may be accomplished.  A maximum of
1900 gallons (12,730 pounds at 6.7 lb/gal) can be loaded in each main
tank by gravity fueling.</para></note>
<note><para>Center tank fueling may be accomplished by transferring
fuel from the main tanks.  A maximum of 2000 pounds of fuel may be
loaded in the center tank with less than full wing tanks, provided
the weight of fuel in the center tank plus actual Zero Fuel Weight
does not exceed Maximum Zero Fuel Weight, and balance limits are observed.</para>
</note>
<note><para>See fueling manual for gravity fueling procedure.</para>
</note>
<warning><para>DO NOT EXCEED 100 GPM FUELING RATE TO PREVENT POSSIBLE
FIRE/EXPLOSION DUE TO STATIC DISCHARGE.</para></warning>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
