<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="26" chg="U" itemnbr="1" key="UPS-757-MEL-00000648" revdate="20080924" revnbr="65" sectnbr="20">
<title>Engine Fire Extinguisher Bottle Pressure Indicating System
&ndash; Fire BTL DISCH Lights </title>
<dispcond btb="YES" category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="2" nbrreq="0"
operation="NO">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided an acceptable test procedure is
used once each flight day to verify that associated bottle is properly
charged.</para>
</remarks>
<placard>
<para>Placard affected BTL DISCH Light (P8) "INOP" and enter item
in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757-MEL-00000649">
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Logbook at the prescribed intervals.
(Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<note><para>Perform once each flight day.</para></note>
<note><para>Bottle charge can be verified two ways: electrically per
step 1) or by weighing the bottle per step 2). If the electrical check
passes, the aircraft may be dispatched. If the electrical check fails,
the failure may be in the pressure switch, and the system may still
be acceptable for dispatch if the bottle charge is verified by weighing.</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Check that the pressure switch is operative, and that
bottle is charged:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Disconnect electrical connector from pressure switch
at bottle with inoperative light circuit.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Connect ohmmeter between pin sockets 1 and 3 of bottle
receptacle.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Check for open circuit indication. Open circuit indicates
pressurized bottle.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Push and hold the pressure switch manual-override
button or turn and hold the ground test hex key 1/4 turn counterclockwise
on the switch and check for closed circuit indication. </para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Release button or hex key and check for open circuit
indication.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Reconnect electrical connector to bottle receptacle.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Optional Procedure:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Remove the bottle per the AMM procedure 26-21-01.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Weigh bottle and compare to the service weight stamped
on the fire bottle (+/- 0.1 pound).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Reinstall serviceable bottle as per AMM.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Cap and stow the affected bottle's Pressure Switch
Connector.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
