<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="28" chg="U" itemnbr="1-2" key="UPS-757-MEL-00000833" revdate="20090814" revnbr="66" sectnbr="41">
<title>Fuel Tank Quantity Indication Systems (Flight Deck) &ndash;
Center Tank Indicator Inop </title>
<dispcond attr-rev="NO" btb="YES" category="C" maintenance="YES"
nbrins="1" nbrreq="0" operation="NO">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Center tank remains empty, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Center tank is verified to be empty before each refueling.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS-757-MEL-00000834">
<note><para>If fuel quantity is entered manually, MANUAL appears following
the entry.  The TOTALIZER display on PROGRESS page 2 is blanked and
fuel quantity from the Fuel Quantity Processor Unit is ignored for
the remainder of the flight.  The FMC now uses calculated fuel quantity.</para>
</note>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS757MELCDL20080604132006">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Center Tank remains empty.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard affected Fuel Quantity Indication "INOP" and enter item
in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757-MEL-00000835">
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Logbook at the prescribed intervals.
(Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>To verify the fuel quantity in associated tank, accomplish
one of the following procedures as appropriate:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Check the associated tank fuel quantity indicator
on the fuel control P28 panel. If it is operative, it may be used
as the means of determining the quantity in the tank with the inoperative
indicator. If it is not operative, placard it inoperative and notify
the fuel crew that the automatic fueling shutoff function may be inoperative.</para>
<para>OR</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Determine the associated tank&rsquo;s fuel quantity
utilizing measuring sticks and the Fuel Measuring Stick Manual provided
with the aircraft. </para>
<note><para>The Fuel Measuring Stick Manual provides instruction for
using the measuring stick readings and a set of conversion tables
that relate stick readings and aircraft attitude to obtain tank quantity.
Ensure that the manual corresponds to the units on the measuring stick
and the weight units of the aircraft configuration. </para></note>
<note><para>With a fuel tank quantity gage inoperative, the total
fuel quantity indication (MEL <refint refid="UPS-757-MEL-00000849"
reftype="MEL">28-41-7-1</refint> and <refint
refid="UPS757MELCDL20080604151459" reftype="MEL">28-41-7-2</refint
>) will be blank.</para></note>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
