<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="21" chg="U" itemnbr="1-2" key="UPS-757-MEL-00000022" revdate="20091120" revnbr="67" sectnbr="25">
<title>Recirculation Fan</title>
<dispcond btb="YES" category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="1" nbrreq="0"
operation="YES">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Both A/C packs and pressurization system are operative,</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Dispatch is prohibited for OAT above 41 degrees C
at departure and destination,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Aircraft remains at or below FL350,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For -200 passenger, combi, and STC ST03562AT procedures
are established and used to ensure aft lower cargo compartment remains
empty or is verified to contain only empty cargo handling equipment,
ballast (ballast may be loaded in ULDs), and/or Fly Away Kits,</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For -200PF and -200SF, procedures are established
and used to ensure forward lower cargo compartment remains empty or
is verified to contain only empty cargo handling equipment, ballast
(ballast may be loaded in ULDs), and/or Fly Away Kits,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For ground operations, at least one pack is operating
for OAT above 18 degrees C,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For ground operations, both packs are operating for
OAT above 32 degrees C, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For passenger and combi ground operations, weather
radar remains OFF except for weather evaluation just before takeoff.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>When recirculation fan is unpowered, DIM function of Indicator
Lights system will be inoperative.</para></note>
<note><para>UPS does not carry Fly Away Kits in voided cargo compartments.</para>
</note>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS-757-MEL-00000023">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Limit flight altitude to FL350.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For ground operations, operate at least one pack for
OAT above 18&ordm;C and both packs for OAT above 32&ordm;C.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>When airborne, observe the (normal) status message
"OVBD EX VAL OPEN" is displayed. This indicates the exhaust valve
is operating in the desired smoke position providing cooling airflow
from differential pressure. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>On engine shutdown, observe the EICAS messages to
be displayed: </para><para>FWD EQ EXH SNSR (MX LEVEL)</para>
<para>EQPT CLG SENSOR (STATUS LEVEL)</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Erase these messages prior to each flight. If messages
do not clear, maintenance action is required.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Ensure the Load Supervisor or authorized personnel
has signed the load manifest. This signature indicates that the load
planning system has accounted for any aircraft load restriction resulting
from the inoperative equipment and that the aircraft has been loaded
in accordance with all UPS weight and balance limitations.</para>
<note><para>When recirculation fan is turned off or inoperative, the
associated pack goes to High Flow mode increasing fuel burn. Add 0.3%
to flight plan fuel. </para></note>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS-757-MEL-00000025">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Limit flight altitude to FL350.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Forward lower cargo compartment remains empty.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Dispatch is prohibited for OAT above 41&ordm;C at
departure and destination. </para></numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>When recirculation fan is turned off or inoperative, the
associated pack goes to High Flow mode increasing fuel burn. Add 0.3%
to flight plan fuel.</para></note>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard Recirc Fan switch "INOP" and enter item in Aircraft
Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757-MEL-00000024">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Observe two advisory level EICAS messages, EQPT OVHT
and L RECIRC FAN displayed, OVHT light illuminated and ground crew
warning horn will sound.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>To extinguish the EQPT OVHT message, light and horn,
locate the forward equipment exhaust low flow sensor TS 5293 through
the forward E/E compartment tunnel right side of nosewheel well. Remove
cap and stow connector D7190.</para>
<note><para>The fan "INOP" light will remain illuminated. All other
functions of EQPT OVHT message light will remain operative.</para>
</note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Prior to each flight, erase the EICAS messages displayed
in item (4) of the Operations Procedure section.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>When forward cargo compartment is to be voided, ensure
all contents are removed from the PFM Box. Include the statement "PFM
Box verified empty" in the deferral statement.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
