<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="34" chg="U" itemnbr="1-0-2" key="UPS-MEL-757-3461102FDK" revdate="20091120" revnbr="67" sectnbr="61">
<title>Flight Management Computer Systems (FMCS) &ndash; Both FMC's/CDU's
Inoperative </title>
<dispcond category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="2" nbrreq="0"
operation="YES">
<remarks>
<para>Except for ER operations, may be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Both Fuel Quantity Indicating System (FQIS) processor
channels are verified to be operative,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>All flight deck fuel quantity indications are operative,
and </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>En route operations do not require its use.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS-MEL-757-3461102OPSFDK">
<para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Both FMCs Inoperative </emphasis
></emphasis></para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Reference AOM Ch. 4, <emphasis role="bold">DISPATCH
WITH BOTH FMC'S INOPERATIVE</emphasis>, for detailed operational considerations.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Complete IRS alignment using the overhead IRS Mode
Selector Panel. Reference AOM Ch. 4, <emphasis role="bold">NAVIGATION</emphasis
>, for detailed procedures.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Use of Engine and Wing Anti-ice is unaffected. Conversion
of TAT and SAT in cruise may be derived from the One Engine INOP chart
in the QRH.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Monitor fuel usage for agreement with flight plan.
At a minimum, verify fuel quantity from top of climb to top of descent
at half hour intervals.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Record zero fuel weight on flight plan to determine
takeoff and landing weights by adding fuel on board.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS-MEL-757-3461102LIMFDK">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Modify the FAA filing suffix to the appropriate code.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>LNAV/VNAV not available to crew.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>FMS RNAV type 1 or 2 SIDS/STARS prohibited.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Route of flight to remain within service volume of
ground based NAV AIDS. RNAV waypoints and procedures not authorized.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>For operations to Central, South American and Mexico destinations
ONLY, the flight may not depart outbound domestic gateways with inoperative
Flight Management Computer (FMC), but may continue series of flights
within the region for the repair interval specified in the Repair
Int Category section.</para></note>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard Both FMC&rsquo;s Control Display Units (M76, M77) "INOP"
and enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-MEL-757-3461102MNTFDK">
<title>Both FMC's INOP</title>
<para>Perform the following test to determine if FQIS processor channels
operate normally:</para>
<note><para>It is preferable that this test be performed with less
than 15,000 lbs (7000 kgs) total fuel.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Apply electrical power per AMM 24-22-00. Close the
battery and RIGHT DC BUS circuit breakers.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the fueling panel door.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open the FUEL QTY L and FUEL QTY R circuit breakers
on the P11 overhead panel.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that the FUEL QTY displays have gone blank.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Test FQIS processor channels:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Close FUEL QTY L circuit breaker, wait ten seconds,
and record the indicated fuel quantity for each tank.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open FUEL QTY L circuit breaker and then close FUEL
QTY R circuit breaker, wait ten seconds, and record the indicated
fuel quantity for each tank.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Compare the quantities recorded in steps 5A and 5B.
If quantities differ by 400 lbs (200 kgs) or less per tank, the fuel
quantity indicating processor unit is acceptable.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
