<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="27" chg="U" itemnbr="2" key="UPS-757-MEL-00000733" revdate="20091120" revnbr="67" sectnbr="32">
<title>Stall Warning/Autoslat System </title>
<dispcond btb="YES" category="A" maintenance="YES" nbrins="2" nbrreq="1"
operation="NO">
<remarks>
<para>One may be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Remaining system is verified to be operative before
each departure, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Operations are limited to not more than three flight
days before repair is made.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<placard>
<para>Placard affected Stall Test switch "L (R) STALL WARNING INOP"
and enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757-MEL-00000734">
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Logbook at the prescribed intervals.
 (Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>For an inoperative stall warning or autoslat function,
check the stall warning BITE module on the P51 panel for fault indication.
 If each BITE does not begin with a "4", a fault indication is present.
 Perform proper maintenance (Ref. MM 27-32-00).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For a failed WEU power supply, check the Warning Electronics
(WEU) Power Supply fault balls.  If a fault ball is present, reset
power supplies.  If either power supply has failed, remove and replace
(Ref. MM 31-51-00).  Dispatch is not permitted with either power supply
inoperative.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For the stickshaker which has failed the test or had
a nuisance activation, open and collar the appropriate stickshaker
circuit breaker on P11 overhead panel (stickshaker - L (11C11); stickshaker
- R (11J20)).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For a nuisance autoslat activation perform the following: </para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Open WARN ELEX A (11J33) and WARN ELEX B (11B18) circuit
breakers on P11 overhead panel.</para>
<caution><para>STATIC SENSITIVE DEVICE.  WEU CONTAINS DEVICES THAT
CAN BE DAMAGED BY STATIC DISCHARGE.  DO NOT HANDLE BEFORE READING
PROCEDURE FOR HANDLING ELECTROSTATIC DISCHARGE SENSITIVE DEVICES (REF.
MM 20-41-01).</para></caution>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open the WARNING ELECTRONICS UNIT P51 panel in the
main E/E bay and remove the stall warning module for the affected
system (system corresponding to the failed autoslat).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>The slats should return to the intermediate position
if they had remained extended after the test.  If the slats remain
extended after removing the stall warning module, dispatch is not
permitted.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Protect and store the removed stall warning module
so it can be returned when a new module is installed.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<para><emphasis role="underline">MAINTENANCE NOTE</emphasis></para>
<para>If a "WARN ELEX" EICAS message is displayed or if the stall
warning/autoslat system failed to operate properly, perform the following
cockpit initiated test prior to each flight to verify that both WEU
power supplies and at least one stall warning/autoslat system is operative.
 The stall warning/autoslat system is considered to be operative if
it activates the stickshaker and autoslat when tested.</para>
<note><para>The speedbrakes/spoilers should be down prior to disconnecting
power from the aircraft.  Ensure control surface areas are clear of
personnel and equipment before movement.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Provide electrical power.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Pull WARN ELEX A (11J33) and WARN ELEX B (11B18) circuit
breakers on the P11 overhead panel.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Reset WARN ELEX A circuit breaker.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Pressurize the left hydraulic system (Ref. Maintenance
Manual 29-11-00).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Position the flap lever to the 1-unit detent.  Verify
that the flaps move to 1 (one) and the slats move to the intermediate
(takeoff) position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Hold both STALL test switches in the STALL position.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that the one (or both) stickshaker(s) is operative
and the slats move to the fully extended (landing) position.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Release the test switches.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that the stickshaker(s) ceases to operate and
the slats retract to the intermediate (takeoff)  position.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Repeat steps 6 through 9 with the WARN ELEX B circuit
breaker in and the WARN ELEX A circuit breaker pulled.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Reset both WARN ELEX A and B circuit breakers.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the stickshaker failed to be operative, the WEU
power supply or both stall warning modules are inoperative.  Dispatch
is not permitted (see MM 31-51-00).</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
