<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="30" chg="U" itemnbr="2-1" key="UPS-757-MEL-00000975" revdate="20080924" revnbr="65" sectnbr="41">
<title>Window Heat INOP Lights &ndash; Associated System Operative </title>
<dispcond btb="YES" category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="4" nbrreq="0"
operation="NO">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided associated window heat system is
verified to be operative before each departure.</para>
</remarks>
<placard>
<para>Placard appropriate Window Heat Light (P5) "LIGHT INOP" and
enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757-MEL-00000976">
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Logbook at the prescribed intervals.
 (Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Verify operation of Window Heat System as follows:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Provide electrical power to left and right main AC
buses. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Press four WINDOW HEAT switches on P5 panel to OFF
(OUT) position. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify the WINDOW HEAT message appears on the EICAS
display.  (This is an advisory level message.)</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Press four WINDOW HEAT switches (P5) to ON (latched-in)
position. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify none of the following EICAS messages are displayed
(these are advisory level messages):</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>WINDOW HEAT</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>L SIDE WINDOW</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>L FWD WINDOW</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>R SIDE WINDOW</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>R FWD WINDOW</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Press the L FWD WINDOW HEAT Switch (P5) to the INOP
(out) position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify  L FWD WINDOW message appears on the EICAS
display.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Press the L FWD WINDOW HEAT switch (P5) to the ON
(latched-in) position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Press the R FWD WINDOW HEAT switch (P5) to the INOP
(out) position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify the R FWD WINDOW message appears on the EICAS
display. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Press the R FWD WINDOW HEAT switch (P5) to the ON
(latched-in) position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Press the L SIDE WINDOW HEAT switch (P5) to the INOP
(out) position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify the L SIDE WINDOW message appears on the EICAS
display. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Press the L SIDE WINDOW HEAT switch (P5) to the ON
(latched-in) position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Press the R SIDE WINDOW HEAT switch (P5) to the INOP
(out) position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify the R SIDE WINDOW message appears on the EICAS
display. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Press the R SIDE WINDOW HEAT switch (P5) to the ON
(latched-in) position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove electrical power if no longer required.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
