<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="29" chg="U" itemnbr="1-1" key="UPS-757-MEL-00000888" revdate="20080924" revnbr="65" sectnbr="32">
<title>Pump OVHT Indication Systems Left, Center, and Right Pump OVHT
Lights &ndash; Pump Operative </title>
<dispcond btb="NO" category="C" maintenance="NO" nbrins="6" nbrreq="3"
operation="YES">
<remarks>
<para>One in each hydraulic system may be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Associated low SYS PRESS light or pump low PRESS light
is operative, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Associated pump is verified to be operative before
each departure.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS757MELCDL20080609115941">
<note><para>During ground operation of the affected pump, to prevent
Hydraulic Pump damage from overheat, do not operate pumps without
a minimum of 600 lbs. of fuel in tanks.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Ensure personnel are clear of flight controls.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Establish electrical power on the aircraft.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Before engine start and prior to selecting HYD pumps
ON, verify associated low SYS PRESS or pump low PRESS light(s) illuminated.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>On the Accessory Panel (P61), select the EICAS Maintenance
Control Switch ELEC/HYD and observe the lower EICAS screen for HYD
PRESS and TEMP.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Select associated HYD pump ON using the following
procedure(s):</para>
<note><para>The pump being tested must be the only pump operating
within the related hydraulic system at the time of the test.</para>
</note>
<para><emphasis role="underline">ENGINE DRIVEN PUMP (EDP)</emphasis
></para>
<note><para><emphasis role="bold">An active brake source is required
when operating an engine.</emphasis></para></note>
<para>-With affected engine running, press ENG pump switch ON.</para>
<para><emphasis role="underline">ELEC HYD PUMP</emphasis></para>
<para>-With electrical power on aircraft, press affected ELEC pump
switch to ON.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify associated (Left, Center, Right) HYD PRESS
reading on EICAS within 2800 to 3200 psig range.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify associated (Left, Center, Right) HYD TEMP reading
on EICAS is less than 80 degrees C.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<placard>
<para>Placard affected Hydraulic Pump OVHT light(s) on Hydraulic Control
panel "INOP" and enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757-MEL-00000889"></maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
