<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="28" chg="U" itemnbr="2-1" key="UPS-757-MEL-00000838" revdate="20091120" revnbr="67" sectnbr="41">
<effect effrg="401420" efftext=""></effect>
<title>Fuel Quantity Processor Channels &ndash; Honeywell FQIS</title>
<dispcond btb="YES" category="B" maintenance="YES" nbrins="2" nbrreq="1"
operation="YES">
<remarks>
<para>Except for ER operations, one channel may be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Total fuel quantity is determined by measuring sticks
or other acceptable means after each refueling, and agrees with fuel
quantity indications, </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Inoperative channel is deactivated by an acceptable
procedure, </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>All flight deck fuel indications are operative,</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For non-PIP and non-Pegasus FMCs, both EICAS computers
are operative,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Fuel flow indications are operative,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>FMC TOTALIZER FUEL quantity agrees with the fuel quantity
indications, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For Pegasus FMCs with Operational Program Software
part number 3418 HNP-02C-08 or earlier, Thrust Management System is
operative.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS-757-MEL-00000839">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Prior to each engine start, confirm that on the FMC
Performance Initialization Page FUEL is automatically initialized
with the known total fuel quantity.  If not, (i.e., boxes appear), <emphasis
role="underline"> DO NOT</emphasis>  manually enter fuel quantity;
repairs must be made before dispatch.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Prior to each engine start, confirm that fuel flow
system inputs are valid on the FMC SENSOR STATUS Page 1 (LEFT and
RIGHT FUEL FLO). </para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<placard>
<para>Placard Fuel Quantity Module on the P5 panel "PROCESSOR CHANNEL
_____ - INOP" and enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757-MEL-00000840">
<title>Fuel Quantity Processor Channels</title>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Isolate and deactivate the malfunctioning channel
with the following procedure.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Apply electrical power per Maintenance Manual 24-22-00.
Close the battery (11C34) and RIGHT DC BUS (11L19) circuit breakers.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the fueling panel door.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that all EICAS circuit breakers are closed.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Press ECS/MSG pushbutton on the P61 panel. If the
FUEL QTY BITE EICAS message is present, conduct a F.Q.I.S. fault detection
BITE check per Maintenance Manual 28-41-00. If the message is not
present, skip to step E.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>If any codes A1 through A5 are displayed, the fault
is in channel 1. If any codes B1 through B5 are displayed, the fault
is in channel 2.</para>
<note><para>If faults exist in both channels, dispatch is not permitted.</para>
</note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Deactivate the faulted channel;</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>If the fault is in channel 1, open the FUEL QTY 1
circuit breaker (11C34), and the FUEL QTY circuit breaker (34A10).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the fault is in channel 2, open the FUEL QTY 2
circuit breaker (11L19) and the FUELING QTY circuit breaker (6E4).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Proceed to step 2.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If in step D the FUEL QTY BITE EICAS message is not
present, conduct the following test.</para>
<note><para>It is preferable that this test be performed with less
than 15,000 lbs total fuel.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Open the FUEL QTY 1 (11C34) and FUEL QTY 2 (11L19)
circuit breakers.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that the FUEL QTY displays have gone blank.</para>
<note><para>If the displays do not blank, verify fueling door closed.</para>
</note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close FUEL QTY 1 circuit breaker (11C34), wait 10
seconds, and record the indicated fuel quantities for each tank; this
tests channel 1.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open FUEL QTY 1 circuit breaker (11C34) and then close
FUEL QTY 2 circuit breaker (11L19), wait 10 seconds. Record the indicated
fuel quantity in each tank; this tests channel 2.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Compare the quantities recorded in steps (3) and (4).
If they differ by more than 400 lbs for any tank, determine the actual
fuel in each tank by using the Measuring Sticks; reference UPS Fueling
Manual B757 Section. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Using the deactivation procedures in step D(2), deactivate
the channel which has the larger difference from the actual fuel quantity. </para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Fuel the aircraft normally on ground power.</para>
<note><para>Do not refuel on battery power with one channel inoperative.</para>
</note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>After each fueling, verify the accuracy of the operative
channel with the following procedure:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>With the fueling door closed, cycle the power on the
active channel by opening the affected FUEL QTY 1 (11C34) or FUEL
QTY 2 (11L19) circuit breaker for 10 seconds and then closing it.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>With the measuring sticks, determine the actual quantity
of fuel in each tank; reference UPS Fueling Manual B757 Section.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Compare the measuring stick quantity with the indicator
quantity for each tank. The channel is operating normally if the stick
quantity and indicator quantity values are within the following limits:</para>
<table frame="none">
<tgroup align="left" cols="1">
<colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.00*"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<para>Main Tank................................................................................................&plusmn;
450 lbs. (200 kg)</para>
<para>Center Tank...........................................................................................&plusmn;
1000 lbs. (450 kg)</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
