<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="28" chg="U" itemnbr="7-1" key="UPS757MELCDL20080604105559" revdate="20100423" revnbr="68" sectnbr="22">
<!--Per C.R.#4381 Bill Bombatch 3/9/10 Considered Inop Item-->
<title>UNIVERSAL FAULT INTERRUPTER (UFI) &ndash; ONE INOPERATIVE</title>
<dispcond attr-rev="NO" category="C" nbrins="2" nbrreq="1">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided associated Center Tank Boost Pump
is considered inoperative.</para>
<note><para>Additional deferral required &ndash; L(R) Center Tank
Boost Pump.</para></note>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPSB757MELCDL20091112120209">
<note><para>Flight crew must perform a manual computation of ZFW +
Center Tank Fuel Weight and compare this value to the maximum ZFW
to ensure that the flight will not exceed MAX ZFW.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Prior to takeoff, verify one crossfeed is open and
remains open until center tank fuel usage is terminated.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Initialize FMC with aircraft's actual weight and balance
ZFW (Basic Operating Weight and payload).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Ensure fuel quantity in main tanks is adequate to
reach a suitable airport.  The low pressure light is operative on
remaining pump, and center tank quantity indication is operative.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Should the operative center fuel pump fail after departure
the center tank fuel plus ZFW must not exceed the maximum ZFW limitation
200,000 lbs. and remains within C.G. limits for landing.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>These restrictions can be verified by applying the
following adjustments to the ZFW/CG values from the original load
manifest:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Add the center tank fuel to the zero fuel weight from
the load manifest.  The zero fuel weight plus center tank fuel must
not exceed the maximum structural zero fuel weight.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>To determine the effect of the center tank fuel on
balance, refer to the following graph.  This graph shows the normal
forward CG limit line and revised forward CG limit lines as a function
of center tank fuel. </para><para>To use the graph, find the appropriate
revised forward CG limit line for the center tank fuel load.</para>
<para>Plot the zero fuel weight, including center tank fuel, versus
the zero fuel weight CG, as shown on the load manifest.</para>
<para>If the point falls aft of the revised forward CG limit, and
forward of the aft CG limit, the aircraft is within balance limits.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<para><emphasis role="underline">EXAMPLE: </emphasis></para>
<table frame="none">
<tgroup align="left" cols="2">
<colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.61*"/>
<colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.39*"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<para>ZFW</para>
</entry>
<entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<para>145,000</para>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<para>Center Tank Fuel</para>
</entry>
<entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<para>15,000</para>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<para>Revised Forward CG</para>
</entry>
<entry colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<para>15</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<note><para>If within balance limits at takeoff, aircraft will remain
within limits whether or not center tank fuel is used.</para></note>
<graphic chapnbr="28" chg="U" key="UPSB757MELCDL20100414084737"
revdate="20100423" revnbr="68" sectnbr="22">
<sheet chg="U" gnbr="MEL_CH_28_Page_7" key="UPSMEL_CH_28_Page_7"
revdate="20100423" revnbr="68"></sheet>
</graphic>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPSB757MELCDL20091112120307">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>The aircraft's ZFW (Basic Operating Weight and payload)
plus center tank fuel weight may not exceed 200,000 lbs.</para>
<note><para>Do not use balance control fuel procedures.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Center tank fuel quantity must be considered unusable
if remaining pump fails.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard near upper EICAS screen "L(R) UNIVERSAL FAULT INTERRUPTER
(UFI) INOP" as appropriate and enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item
Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPSB757MELCDL20091112120457">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Open and collar affected pump C/B  on P6:</para><para
> L OVRD - P6F14&#9;R OVRD - P6F20</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
