<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="31" chg="U" itemnbr="4-1" key="UPS757MEL21486101JDM57813" revdate="20080924" revnbr="65" sectnbr="61">
<title>EICAS Status Messages &ndash; Associated Equipment Operative</title>
<dispcond btb="NO" category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="96" nbrreq="0"
operation="YES">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided associated equipment is verified
to be operative before each departure.</para>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS-757-MEL-00JDM061040156">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Attempt to clear EICAS status message using EICAS
STATUS MESSAGE CLEARING PROCEDURE in Chapter 4 of AOM.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<placard>
<para>Placard near upper EICAS display "(Specific EICAS Message) INOP"
and enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS757DMP21458SAJDM25497">
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Logbook at the prescribed intervals.
(Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>An inoperative STATUS message is one which is displayed
when there is no actual equipment fault. The equipment with the inoperative
STATUS message must be checked for normal operation prior to each
departure per the associated Maintenance Manual operational procedure.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If normal equipment operation cannot be verified,
MEL dispatch deviations for the associated equipment must be observed,
see MEL <refint refid="UPS757MEL65874JDM7369" reftype="MEL">31-61-4-2</refint
>. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Accomplish the appropriate procedures for the following
EICAS Status messages:</para><para>L (R) OIL SCAV VAL (PW Only)</para>
<para>FUEL QTY CHANNEL</para>
<para>POWER XFER UNIT</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<para><emphasis role="bold">EICAS STATUS MESSAGES</emphasis></para>
<para>L(R) OIL SCAV VAL (PW Only)</para>
<para>The following procedure can be used to verify normal operation
of the #4 bearing scavenge valve for PW engines when the Status message
"L(R) OIL SCAV VAL" is displayed.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Confirm that the scavenge valve operates normally
and #4 carbon seal is intact by operating the engine on the ground
at an N<sub>2</sub> speed greater than 88% or reading data taken from
an EICAS manual event with a burner pressure greater than 300 psig
and verifying the following parameters on the EICAS Perf/APU page,
the Status page, and the Exceedence page.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Verify Scavenge Oil Pressure (SCAV) shown on the Perf/APU
page is between 45 and 155 psig.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that there has not been a Main Oil Temperature
exceedence on the previous flight.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that there has not been a step increase in
oil consumption. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that the affected engine does not display any
of the following EICAS messages:</para><para>L(R) ENG OIL SEAL</para>
<para>L(R) OIL FILTER</para>
<para>L(R) OIL SCAV OPEN</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Determine dispatchability.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Dispatch is not permitted if any of the above tests
are failed. Refer to the MM 79-21-00 for trouble shooting procedures.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If all the tests in Step 1 are passed, the L(R) OIL
SCAV VAL message is a nuisance message and dispatch is permitted.
Placard the inflight log "L(R) ENGINE #4 SCAVENGE VALVE PROXIMITY
SENSOR INOP".</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<para>FUEL QTY CHANNEL</para>
<para>The following procedure can be used to verify normal operation
of the FQIS when the Status message "FUEL QTY CHANNEL" is displayed. </para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Record last flight leg fault to develop fault history.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Run the FQIS self test.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If no faults are displayed, the "FUEL QTY CHANNEL"
message is a nuisance message and dispatch is permitted.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<para>POWER XFER UNIT</para>
<para>The following procedure can be used to verify normal operation
of the Power Transfer Unit when the Status message "POWER XFER UNIT"
is displayed.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Display ELEC/HYD on EICAS.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Power right hydraulic system with ACMP (Left ACMP
is OFF). </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open the right Speed Card circuit breaker (11B32).
This removes electrical power from the right Engine Out relay.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify left Hydraulic system pressure is high (PTU
is ON). </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Turn OFF right ACMP.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Confirm right hydraulic system pressure decays to
less than 100 psi (pumps OFF).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Confirm left hydraulic system pressure decays to less
than 100 psi (pumps OFF).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Switch right ACMP ON and confirm pressure rises in
right hydraulic system.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that no rise in left hydraulic system pressure
occurs. If a rise in left hydraulic system pressure occurs, either
the control pressure switch (S10129), the PTU relay (K10051), or the
time delay (M10145) has failed. Rise in the left hydraulic system
means no dispatch is allowed.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the right Speed Card circuit breaker (11B32).
This provides electrical power to the right engine out relay and recycles
the relays.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Erase the ECS/HYD Maintenance Page.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Start right engine. (Configuration: EDPs ON, left
and right ACMPs ON)</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Turn the left ACMP OFF.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify left hydraulic pressure is high.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Start left engine.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Turn OFF left EDP and verify left ACMP remains OFF.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify left hydraulic system pressure remains high.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Turn left EDP ON.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify EDP Low Pressure light goes out.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Pull hydraulic PTU control circuit breaker (11D31).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Turn left EDP OFF.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify left system pressure is low.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close circuit breaker (11D31) and verify left hydraulic
system pressure is high.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Restore system to normal.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
