<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="78" chg="U" itemnbr="1-1" key="UPS_MEL_JDM412154SA783101" revdate="20090814" revnbr="66" sectnbr="31">
<title>THRUST REVERSERS &ndash; RB211</title>
<dispcond btb="YES" category="C" downgrade="CATEGORY 1/2/3a"
maintenance="YES" nbrins="2" nbrreq="1" operation="YES">
<remarks>
<para>One may be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Inoperative reverser is secured in forward thrust
position, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Appropriate performance adjustments are applied.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>No performance adjustments required on UPS aircraft.</para>
</note>
<note><para>During landing roll-out, differential braking may be required
to maintain directional control.</para></note>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS-757-OPS-2JDM56411342">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Asymmetrical reverse thrust may be used. Use normal
reversing procedures and techniques. If it appears that rudder authority
is becoming limited during deceleration, return lever to reverse idle
detent.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Land and Hold Short Operations (LAHSO) prohibited.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS-757-OPS-0SA44578465">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Downgrade aircraft dispatch category status to CAT
3a.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Land and Hold Short Operations (LAHSO) prohibited.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>No dispatch with any reverser message displayed for
operative reverser.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>Must be operative for dispatch into LPB, UIO, BOG, GUA,TGU.</para>
</note>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard affected Reverser Thrust Lever "REVERSER INOP" and enter
item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS-757DMP7831SA54651">
<title>Thrust Reversers</title>
<para>Deferral of this item requires downgrading to the status indicated
in the A/C STATUS DISPATCH column below.</para>
<table>
<tgroup align="center" cols="3">
<colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.99*"/>
<colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.01*"/>
<colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.01*"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry valign="top">
<para><emphasis role="bold">INOP POSITION</emphasis></para>
</entry>
<entry valign="top">
<para><emphasis role="bold">NUMBER INOP</emphasis></para>
</entry>
<entry valign="top">
<para><emphasis role="bold">A/C STATUS DISPATCH</emphasis></para>
</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<para>&mdash;</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>1</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>CAT 3a</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<para><emphasis role="bold">P&amp;W ENGINE</emphasis></para>
<note><para>Dispatch is permitted with one or both sync-locks inoperative
provided sync-locks are verified inoperative in the "locked" position.
 The following verification of inoperative sync-locks does not need
to be performed if it is known the sync-locks are operating normally.</para>
</note>
<para>Verification of sync-lock in locked position:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Open fan cowl panels per AMM 71-11-04-2.</para>
<caution><para>DO NOT USE AN EXTENSION BAR OR OTHER TOOLS TO MOVE
THE UNLOCK LEVER.  IF YOU USE AN EXTENSION BAR OR OTHER TOOLS, DAMAGE
TO THE UNLOCK LEVER OR ACTUATOR CAN OCCUR.</para></caution>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Operate the unlock handle on the thrust reverser locking
actuator to the unlocked position, and then release.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that both left and right translating sleeves
do not move aft more than approximately one sixteenth of an inch.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Deactivate the thrust reverser per the normal procedure.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<para>Normal Deactivation of Inoperative Thrust Reverser:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Open fan cowl panels per AMM 71-11-04-2.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open aft fairing access door.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Obtain isolation valve deactivation pin B78001-3 (part
of B78001-2 Dispatch Kit) from the nacelle stowage location or the
fly-away equipment stowage container in the forward cargo compartment.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Install deactivation pin in the manual lockout hole
on the thrust reverser isolation valve and install cotter pin or lockwire.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Depress the bypass valve handle on the thrust reverser
isolation valve and install a streamered deactivation pin (0.125 inch
diameter X 1.1 inch, part of B78001-1 lock assembly).</para>
<note><para>The streamer pins and the hitch pins are found in the
deactivation pin container on the forward surface of the isolation
valve (if installed).</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the sleeve is extended, turn manual drive with
3/8 inch square drive to retract per AMM 78-31-00-2.  Manual cranking
of the sleeve will return sleeve to within approximately 0.75 inch
of the stowed position. </para>
<note><para>The manual drive has an override clutch which limits the
amount of torque that can be applied.  Due to seal forces, the clutch
will ratchet before the sleeve is fully retracted and locking is complete.</para>
</note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove the two thrust reverser sleeve plugs.  Loosen
the primary deactivation eyebolt nut until the eyebolt can be aligned
with the hole in the thrust reverser sleeve.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove the two deactivation pins from the stowage
position below the center hydraulic actuator.  Install the sleeve
plugs in the deactivation pin stowage position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Perform the following to unlock the sync-locks.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Verify that the following circuit breakers are closed:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>AIR/GND SYS 1  (11S15)</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>AIR/GND SYS 2  (11S19)</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>LANDING GEAR POS SYS 1  (11C30)</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>LANDING GEAR POS SYS 2  (11C23)</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>SYNC-LOCK-L or SYNC-LOCK-R  (L=6C12 or R=6D12)</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Supply electrical power (Ref AMM 24-22-00).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Raise the left (right) reverse thrust lever to the
deploy position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Install primary deactivation pin through the thrust
reverser sleeve into the primary deactivation eyebolt.</para>
<caution><para>MAKE SURE THAT THE MANUAL DRIVE IS FULLY ENGAGED WITH
THE SYNC-LOCK DRIVE SHAFT BEFORE ROTATION AND THAT IT STAYS FULLY
ENGAGED DURING THE FULL ROTATION.  IF THE MANUAL DRIVE IS NOT FULLY
ENGAGED, DAMAGE TO THE SYNC-LOCK CAN OCCUR.</para></caution>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Tighten the primary deactivation eyebolt nut to retract
the thrust reverser sleeve until the secondary deactivation pin can
be installed through the thrust reverser sleeve into the torque box
structure.</para>
<note><para>If the sync-locks cannot be electrically unlocked per
step 9, it will be necessary to unlock the sync-lock manually by engaging
the manual drive and rotating the manual drive in the stow direction
while at the same time tightening the primary deactivation eyebolt
nut.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify the locking feature on the deactivation pins
and/or captive nuts as follows:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Fully engage the deactivation pin in the thrust reverser
captive nut.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Measure the "breakaway" torque value as the deactivation
pin is rotated in the remove direction until the locking feature on
the pin and/or nut is disengaged.</para>
<note><para>There should be no axial load on the captive nut when
the torque is measured.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Make sure the deactivation pin and/or captive nut
have a minimum breakaway torque of 18 inch-pounds.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the deactivation pin and captive nut combination
include a breakaway torque of less than 18 inch-pounds, replace the
deactivation pin and/or captive nut as necessary.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Tighten both deactivation pins to 120 to 150 pound-inches. </para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Repeat steps 6-15 for the opposite reverser sleeve.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move the left (right) reverse thrust lever to the
stow position. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove the streamered pin from the bypass valve handle
on the thrust reverser isolation valve allowing the valve to return
to its normally closed position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close aft fairing access door.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close fan cowl panels per AMM 71-11-04-2.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open and collar the appropriate SYNC-LOCK circuit
breakers.  For the left engine, the L ENG SYNC-CONTROL (6C12).  For
the right engine, the R ENG SYNC-LOCK CONTROL (6D12).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify thrust control operates normally:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Prior to engine start, move the EEC POWER switch on
the EEC Maintenance Panel (P61) to the ALTN position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Advance thrust levers to the full forward position.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that the Thrust Level Resolver (TLR) measurements
on the EICAS EPCS page read between 80 - 83 degrees for associated
engine.</para>
<note><para>If the angle is not in the given range, then adjust the
control rod(s) per AMM 76-11-00-5.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move the thrust levers to the idle position.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that the TLR measurements on the EICAS EPCS
page read 38.0 +/- 0.2 degrees.</para>
<note><para>If the angle is not in the given range, then adjust the
control rod(s) per AMM 76-11-00-5.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that the RVA measurement on the EICAS EPCS
page reads 0 +/- 2.0 for the PRI and SEC channels of both EECs.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move the EEC POWER switch to the NORM position.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<graphic chapnbr="78" chg="U" confnbr="1" key="UPS757DMPFIG7803"
revdate="20080924" revnbr="65" sectnbr="31">
<sheet chg="U" gnbr="DMP_CH_78_Page_3" key="UPSDMP_CH_78_Page_3"
revdate="20080924" revnbr="65"></sheet>
</graphic>
<graphic chapnbr="78" chg="U" key="UPS757DMPFIG7804" revdate="20080924"
revnbr="65" sectnbr="31">
<sheet chg="U" gnbr="DMP_CH_78_Page_4" key="UPSDMP_CH_78_Page_4"
revdate="20080924" revnbr="65">
<title>THRUST REVERSER ISOLATION VALVE DEACTIVATION</title>
</sheet>
</graphic>
<graphic chapnbr="78" chg="U" key="UPS757DMPFIG7805" revdate="20080924"
revnbr="65" sectnbr="31">
<sheet chg="U" gnbr="DMP_CH_78_Page_5" key="UPSDMP_CH_78_Page_5"
revdate="20080924" revnbr="65">
<title>PW ENGINE</title>
</sheet>
</graphic>
<para><emphasis role="bold">RB211 ENGINE</emphasis></para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Stow thrust reverser, if deployed, per AMM 78-31-00,
Manually (Stow) Retract the Thrust Reverser, or Retract (Stow) the
Thrust Reverser with Hydraulic Power.</para>
<note><para>The ground maintenance thrust reverser deactivation procedure
must first be accomplished prior to manually stowing the thrust reverser.
 The AMM CAUTION to not use the ground maintenance deactivation procedure
for flight dispatch is appropriate because the procedure is used only
while manually stowing the thrust reverser.  After manually stowing
the thrust reverser, the thrust reverser activation procedure must
be accomplished before proceeding with the following DDG deactivation
procedural steps.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open aft fairing access door.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Obtain isolation valve deactivation pin B78001-3 (part
of B78001-2 Dispatch Kit) from the nacelle stowage location or the
fly-away equipment stowage container in the forward cargo compartment.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Install deactivation pin in the manual lockout hole
on the thrust reverser isolation valve and install cotter pin or lockwire.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove mechanical deactivation pin from stowage hole
on both translating sleeves of inoperative thrust reverser.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove plug from lockout hole on both translating
sleeves of inoperative reverser and install in stowage hole.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Install mechanical deactivation pin in lockout hole
of right translating sleeve of the inoperative thrust reverser.  If
pin cannot be installed continue with step 7A; otherwise proceed to
step 8.</para>
<note><para>When installed, mechanical deactivation pin will protrude
0.83 &plusmn; 0.03 in. (20-22mm).</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Manually unlock the lower locking actuator on the
right thrust reverser translating sleeve (Ref. AMM 78-31-00-2) and
restrain the unlock lever in the unlocked position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Depress the bypass valve handle on the thrust reverser
isolation valve and install a streamered pin (0.125 inch diameter
X 1.1 inch).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Insert 3/8 in. square drive into the external drive
socket of the right translating sleeve.</para>
<caution><para>MAXIMUM TORQUE PERMITTED DURING MANUAL STOWAGE IS 165
POUND-INCHES (18.6 NM).</para></caution>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Push the drive to engage, then crank counter-clockwise
until 165 pound-inches (18.6 NM) torque is reached; release pressure.
 Install mechanical deactivation pin.  (If necessary repeat step three
times.)</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Manually unlock the left translating sleeve locking
actuator and restrain the unlock lever in the unlocked position.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Insert  3/8 in. square drive into the external drive
socket of the left translating sleeve.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Push the drive to engage, then apply 160 &plusmn;
5 lb-in torque clockwise.  Verify that the left translating sleeve
does not deploy (slight movement is acceptable).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove the restraint from the left translating sleeve
actuator unlock lever and allow it to return to the locked position.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Install mechanical deactivation pin in lockout hole
of left translating sleeve of the inoperative thrust reverser.  If
pin cannot be installed continue with step 12A; otherwise proceed
to step 13.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Insert 3/8 in. square drive into the external drive
socket of the left translating sleeve.</para>
<caution><para>MAXIMUM TORQUE PERMITTED DURING MANUAL STOWAGE IS 165
POUND-INCHES (18.6 NM).</para></caution>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Push the drive to engage, then crank counter-clockwise
until 165 pound-inches (18.6 NM) torque is reached; release pressure.
 Install mechanical deactivation pin.  (If necessary repeat step three
times).</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove the streamered pin from the bypass valve handle
on the thrust reverser isolation valve allowing the valve to return
to its normally closed position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close aft fairing access door.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Pull and collar the affected sync lock circuit breaker(s). </para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>LH  engine</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>On main power distribution P6:  L ENG SYNC-LOCK CONTROL
(6C12) </para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>RH engine</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>On main power distribution P6:  R ENG SYNC-LOCK CONTROL</para>
<para>                                                       ALTN
(6D12)</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>On overhead circuit breaker panel P11:  R ENG SYNC-LOCK</para>
<para>                                                           
       CONTROL (11K32)</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<graphic chapnbr="78" chg="U" key="UPS757MELCDL20080723111844"
revdate="20080924" revnbr="65" sectnbr="31">
<sheet chg="U" gnbr="DMP_CH_78_Page_8a" key="UPS757MELCDL20080723111923"
revdate="20080924" revnbr="65" sheetnbr="001">
<title>THRUST REVERSER ACTUATOR MANUAL LOCK AND CRANK LOCATIONS</title>
</sheet>
</graphic>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
