<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="27" chg="U" itemnbr="1-1" key="UPS747MEL20070815103210" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="41">
<title>Stabilizer Trim/ Rudder Ratio Changer Modules (SRM) &ndash;
Stabilizer Trim Control</title>
<dispcond category="C" downgrade="CATEGORY 2" maintenance="YES"
nbrins="2" nbrreq="1" operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>Stabilizer trim control in one module may be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Horizontal stabilizer is verified to be operative
with the Alternate Stab Trim Switches, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Rudder ratio control in both modules are operative.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>If Stabilizer Trim control in the other SRM fails, autopilot
will not be available.</para></note>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815103211">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>STAB AUTO CUTOUT</para>
<para>STAB AUTO TRIM</para>
<para>STAB TRIM</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Manual stabilizer trim control is available from either
control wheel trim switch. However, stabilizer will move at one-half
drive speed. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Autotrim may be affected as follows:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>In cruise, if the left SRM stabilizer trim control
is inoperative, the left autopilot will not engage because the left
FCC will not receive a valid signal from the SRM. Similarly, the right
autopilot will not engage if the right SRM trim control is inoperative.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>After arming APP mode when autoland status displays
LAND 2 or LAND 3, the FCCs ignore the SRM valid signal input, allowing
all autopilots to engage. Normal (half-rate) autotrim control is retained
by the fully operative SRM.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Speed Stability Trim and Mach Trim are operative.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Inflight failure of the other SRM, or stabilizer trim
control in the other SRM, will result in the loss of all autotrim
capability and possible loss of all autotrim capability and possible
loss of manual trim from both of the control wheel trim switches.
Stabilizer trim control may only be available through the Alternate
Stabilizer Trim Switches.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>The EICAS advisory message >STAB TRIM 2 or >STAB TRIM
3 may remain displayed. Also, the message may be cleared when the
stabilizer is moved with the Alternate Stabilizer Trim Switches and
reappear when using the control wheel trim switches due to half drive
speed stabilizer movement. </para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MEL20070815103212">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Downgrade Aircraft Category Dispatch Status to CAT
2.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard below Captain&rsquo;s PFD on P-1-1 panel: "STAB TRIM
CONTROL IN L (R) SRM INOP". Enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log. </para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815103213">
<para>Deferral of this item requires downgrading to the status indicated
in the A/C STATUS DISPATCH column below.</para>
<table>
<tgroup align="center" cols="3">
<colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.00*"/>
<colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.04*"/>
<colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.96*"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">INOP POSITION</emphasis></para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">NUMBER INOP</emphasis></para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">A/C STATUS DISPATCH</emphasis></para>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<para>&ndash;</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>1</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>CAT 2</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<warning><para>ENSURE THAT PERSONNEL AND EQUIPMENT ARE CLEAR OF ALL
FLIGHT CONTROL SURFACES.</para></warning>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Provide electrical power to aircraft and pressurize
hydraulic systems 2 and 3.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that stabilizer is operative with the Alternate
Stabilizer Trim switches:</para>
<note><para>During the following tests, the EICAS advisory messages
>STAB TRIM 2 and >STAB TRIM 3 will display, along with the status
message STAB TRIM. <emphasis role="bold">If both advisory messages
>STAB TRIM 2 and >STAB TRIM 3 remain displayed at the conclusion of
the tests, dispatch is not allowed</emphasis>. </para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Ensure stabilizer trim cutout switches and cutout
valves operate normally:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Select STAB TRIM 2 CUT OUT and STAB TRIM 3 CUT OUT
position on the guarded Stabilizer Trim Cutout Switches located on
the control stand. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Using both Alternate Stabilizer Trim Switches located
on the control stand, select APL NOSE UP for at least 3 seconds. Monitor
stabilizer trim indicator to confirm the stabilizer does not move.
If the stabilizer does move, dispatch is not allowed until repairs
are made.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Using both Alternate Stabilizer Trim Switches, select
APL NOSE DN for at least 3 seconds. Monitor stabilizer trim indicator
to confirm the stabilizer does not move. If the stabilizer does move,
dispatch is not allowed until repairs are made.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the guards on both the STAB TRIM 2 and STAB
TRIM 3 Stabilizer Trim Cutout Switches.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that no alternate trim solenoid valve is failed
in the energized position:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Move the left Alternate Stabilizer Trim Switch in
both the aircraft nose up and aircraft nose down directions. Verify
the stabilizer does not move. If the stabilizer does move, an arm
or control solenoid valve within a STCM (Stabilizer Trim Control Module)
is failed in the energized position and dispatch is not allowed until
repairs are made.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Move the right Alternate Stabilizer Trim Switch in
both the aircraft nose up and aircraft nose down directions. Verify
the stabilizer does not move. If the stabilizer does move, an arm
or control solenoid valve within a STCM (Stabilizer Trim Control Module)
is failed in the energized position and dispatch is not allowed until
repairs are made.</para>
<note><para>If the EICAS advisory message >STAB TRIM 2 is displayed,
perform step D <emphasis role="underline">before</emphasis> step C
below:</para></note>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Ensure stabilizer is operative using Hydraulic System
2 as follows:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Select STAB TRIM 3 CUT OUT position on the guarded
Stabilizer Trim Cutout Switch located on the control stand.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Using both Alternate Stabilizer Trim Switches, select
APL NOSE UP for at least 3 seconds. Monitor stabilizer trim indicator
to confirm motion of stabilizer in aircraft nose up direction. Note
that the stabilizer will move at one half drive speed. If the stabilizer
does not move, dispatch is not allowed.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Using both Alternate Stabilizer Trim Switches, select
APL NOSE DN for at least 3 seconds. Monitor stabilizer trim indicator
to confirm motion of stabilizer in aircraft nose down direction. Note
that the stabilizer will move at one half drive speed. If the stabilizer
does not move, dispatch is not allowed.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the guard on the STAB TRIM 3 Stabilizer Trim
Cutout Switch.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Ensure stabilizer is operative using Hydraulic System
3 as follows:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Select STAB TRIM 2 CUT OUT position on the guarded
Stabilizer Trim Cutout Switch located on the control stand.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Using both Alternate Stabilizer Trim Switches, select
APL NOSE UP for at least 3 seconds. Monitor stabilizer trim indicator
to confirm motion of stabilizer in aircraft nose up direction. Note
that the stabilizer will move at one half drive speed. If the stabilizer
does not move, dispatch is not allowed.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Using both Alternate Stabilizer Trim Switches, select
APL NOSE DN for at least 3 seconds. Monitor stabilizer trim indicator
to confirm motion of stabilizer in aircraft nose down direction. Note
that the stabilizer will move at one half drive speed. If the stabilizer
does not move, dispatch is not allowed.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the guard on the STAB TRIM 2 Stabilizer Trim
Cutout Switch.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Dispatch is not allowed with rudder ratio control
inoperative in either the left or right SRM. To confirm that rudder
ratio control is functioning properly in both modules, verify EICAS
status message RUDDER RATIO is not displayed.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
