<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="32" chg="U" itemnbr="1-3" key="UPS747MEL20070815104135" revdate="20090824" revnbr="7" sectnbr="41">
<title>Wheel Brakes &ndash; Brake(s) Removed</title>
<dispcond category="C" downgrade="CATEGORY 3a" maintenance="YES"
nbrins="16" nbrreq="14" operation="YES">
<remarks>
<para>One or two brakes may be deactivated by removing the brake(s)
and capping the lines provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Takeoff and landing performance complies with AOM/AA
Data, both for Gear Down dispatch and for two brakes deactivated,
and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>After takeoff, gear remains down for two minutes before
retraction, and.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If inoperative brake(s) are on wheels other than No.
1, 2, 13, or 14, one forward and one aft brake on the same side must
be removed to maintain a balanced truck, or if inoperative brake(s)
are on wheels No. 1, 2, 13, or 14, one brake on each affected truck
may be removed.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815104136">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Maximum takeoff thrust must be used.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Stopping distances will increase.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Leave gear down for a minimum of 2 minutes after takeoff
to permit affected wheel(s) to spin down prior to gear retraction.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Observe performance limitations.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>At takeoff weights greater than 720,000 lbs. flaps up
maneuver speed (V<sub>REF</sub>+ 100 kt) may exceed the landing gear
retract speed (270 kt.). Therefore, ensure gear is retracted prior
to selecting Flaps Up.</para></note>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MEL20070815104137">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Downgrade Aircraft Category Dispatch Status to CAT
3a.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Compute V1 using the V1 correction, One or Two Brakes
Deactivated or One or Two Anti-Skid Channels Inoperative worksheet
in the AOM Chapter 5.1. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Apply takeoff performance runway weight corrections
from the Takeoff Runway Limit Weight Reduction, Landing Gear Extended
or Brake(s) Deactivated By Capping chart found in the AOM Chapter
5.1.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Apply restricted takeoff climb weights from the Takeoff
Climb Limit Weight, Landing Gear Extended or Brake(s) Deactivated
By Capping chart found in the AOM Chapter 5.1.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Apply landing weight performance for 1 or 2 brakes
deactivated in the AA landing data.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If "Obstacle Clearance Altitude (OCA)" is present
on the AA Data for the departure runway, contact Flight Control for
alternate AA Data.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Operations on cluttered or icy runways prohibited.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Use cutback runway is prohibited.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard below Captain&rsquo;s PFD on P-1-1 panel: "WHEEL___
BRAKE(S) DEACTIVATED &ndash; BRAKE(S) REMOVED". Enter item in Aircraft
Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815104138">
<para>Deferral of this item requires downgrading to the status indicated
in the A/C STATUS DISPATCH column below.</para>
<table>
<tgroup align="center" cols="3">
<colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.00*"/>
<colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.00*"/>
<colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.00*"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">INOP POSITION</emphasis></para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">NUMBER INOP</emphasis></para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">A/C STATUS DISPATCH</emphasis></para>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<para>&ndash;</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>2</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>CAT 3a</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<note><para>If Brake System Control Unit (BSCU) P/N S283U002-5 or
later version is installed and one or two brakes are deactivated,
advisory message ANTI-SKID for the affected wheels may be inhibited
as follows: Rotate the BSCU (E9 Rack) message inhibit knobs on the
unit&rsquo;s front face so that one knob points to each affected wheel&rsquo;s
position number. Advisory level message ANTI-SKID will not display
if an anti-skid fault is present. While en route, if an additional
anti-skid fault occurs affecting another wheel, EICAS will again display
ANTI-SKID. </para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>REMOVE INOPERATIVE BRAKE(S):</para>
<note><para>To ensure that the truck will tilt to the retract position,
one forward and one aft brake on the same side must be removed to
maintain a balanced truck. It may be necessary to remove or relocate
an operative brake in order to balance the truck and ensure proper
retraction. However, if the inoperative brake(s) is on wheel No. 1,
2, 13 or 14, one brake on each affected truck may be removed.</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Remove the affected brakes (AMM 32-41-15).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Cap and secure the hydraulic lines and electrical
wiring for the affected brakes, using procedures below:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Remove pressure from hydraulic systems 1, 2 and 4
(AMM 29-11-00/201). </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Release the parking brake.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Release pressure from the hydraulic brake accumulator
by operating the brake pedals until HYD BRAKE PRESS gauge on the P1
panel shows pre-charge pressure (approximately 750 psi).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Uncouple the Brake Disconnect - Brake Hose Half and
attach the hose to the landing gear truck using tie-wrap P/N BACS38K3D
or P/N PLT2S-C3. This will ensure that the hose will not interfere
with brake rotation when the gear is retracted.</para>
<note><para>The part of the Brake Disconnect that is attached to the
hose is called the Brake Disconnect - Brake hose half. The part of
the Brake Disconnect that is attached to the brake is called the Brake
Disconnect &ndash; Brake Half. </para></note>
<note><para>The Brake Disconnect incorporates a pressure release function
in the Brake Half; there is no need to open the brake bleed fitting
for dispatch. </para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Pressurize hydraulic system 1, 2 or 4.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Apply brake pressure and check for leaks.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove the associated brake equalizer rods from the
truck. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Install tire and wheel assemblies and restore the
aircraft to normal (AMM 23-41-15).</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
