<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="36" chg="U" itemnbr="1" key="UPS747MEL20070815104915" revdate="20090824" revnbr="7" sectnbr="11">
<title>Engine Bleed Pressure Regulating and Shutoff Valves &ndash;
(PRSOV)</title>
<dispcond attr-rev="NO" category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="4"
nbrreq="3" operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>One may be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Associated PRSOV is secured closed except for engine
start, </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>L and R ISLN valves are open for takeoff, and when
flaps are operated,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Bleed systems on remaining engines are operative,
and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Start valves on remaining engine are operative.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815104916">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>ENG ___ START VLV</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>A manual override ground start is required.</para>
<note><para>The amount of torque necessary to open the PRSOV depends
on existing pneumatic pressure. If manifold is unpressurized, the
PRSOV will open easily. If manifold is pressurized, the PRSOV may
require up to 50 ft-lb. of applied torque to open.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>If PRSOV is to be opened with wing pneumatic manifold
unpressurized: </para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Select the appropriate L or R ISLN VALVE switch OFF.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the other engine on the same wing is running, select
its ENGINE BLEED switch OFF.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>When ready for engine start, advise ground crew to
open the PRSOV.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Ensure the pneumatic manifold is pressurized and pull
the appropriate engine start switch.</para>
<note><para>If PRSOV is opened with the wing pneumatic manifold unpressurized,
select appropriate L or R ISLN VALVE switch ON after PRSOV is confirmed
open by ground crew.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>At 45-50% N<sub>2</sub>, request closed PRSOV to ground
crew. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Continue engine start.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Select ENGINE BLEED switch OFF when requested by ground
crew to enable them to secure the PRSOV closed.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Select ON for the associated ENGINE BLEED switch after
ground crew has secured the PRSOV locked closed. This enables other
engine valves to be operative.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Ensure ENGINE BLEED switch for other engine on same
wing is selected ON.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>APU-TO-PACK TAKEOFF procedure is not permitted since
L and R ISLN valves must remain open during takeoff.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Starter assisted inflight start is not available for
the affected engine.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>During takeoff and for all flap operations, ensure
that the L and R ISLN valve switches are in the open position. This
assures air is available for operation of the air-driven hydraulic
demand pump and LE flaps in the event of an adjacent engine shutdown.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MEL20070815104917">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>APU-TO-PACK TAKEOFF procedure is not permitted.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard adjacent to associated ENGINE BLEED switch on the Bleed
Air Control panel (P5): "ENG_PRSOV INOP CLOSED". Placard adjacent
to associated START switch on the Engine Ignition and Start Control
panel (P5): "ENG_STARTER INOP INFLIGHT". Enter items in Aircraft Deferred
Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815104918">
<graphic chapnbr="36" chg="U" confnbr="1" key="UPS747MEL20070815104919"
revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="11">
<sheet chg="U" gnbr="747-400_DMP_CH_36_Page_1"
key="UPS747MEL20070815104920" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5"></sheet>
</graphic>
<para>The PRSOV is installed in the strut. Access to the PRSOV manual
override drive is on the left side of the strut. It is not necessary
to open any access panels to operate the PRSOV manual override drive.
The PRSOV is spring loaded to the closed position. It can be manually
held in the open position for engine starting. After engine start,
the inoperative PRSOV must be manually placed in the locked closed
position.</para>
<para><emphasis role="bold">Special Tools and Equipment: G71021-6
&ndash; Drive Extension &ndash; Starter Valve and PRSOV.</emphasis
></para>
<warning><para>DO NOT OPERATE THE THRUST REVERSER DURING MANUAL OPERATION
OF THE PRSOV. THRUST REVERSER OPERATION DURING MANUAL OPERATION OF
THE PRSOV CAN CAUSE SERIOUS PERSONNEL INJURY AND DAMAGE.</para>
</warning>
<warning><para>DO NOT USE ENGINE NACELLE SERVICE INTERPHONE JACK ON
ENGINE WHICH IS TO BE STARTED OR ON ENGINE IN OPERATION. PERSONNEL
COULD ENTER HAZARD AREA RESULTING IN SERIOUS INJURY OR LOSS OF LIFE.</para>
</warning>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Establish interphone communication with the flight
deck and determine if the applicable wing manifold will be pressurized
or unpressurized for associated engine start.</para>
<note><para>The amount of torque necessary to open the PRSOV depends
on existing pneumatic pressure.  If manifold is unpressurized, the
PRSOV will open easily.  If manifold is  pressurized, the PRSOV may
require up to 50 ft-lb of applied torque to open.</para></note>
<caution><para><emphasis role="bold">DO NOT ROTATE THE MANUAL OVERRIDE
DRIVE QUICKLY WHEN THERE IS NO WING MANIFOLD PNEUMATIC PRESSURE. 
FAST OPERATION OF THE MANUAL OVERRIDE DRIVE MAY RESULT IN TEMPORARY
JAMMING OF THE ACTUATOR OR POSSIBLE DIAPHRAGM DAMAGE.</emphasis></para>
</caution>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>When requested by the flight crew, slowly turn the
PRSOV manual override drive 90&ordm; clockwise to the open position.
 Hold it in the open position until the flight crew requests a closed
PRSOV.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>When flight crew requests closed PRSOV, turn the PRSOV
manual override drive 90&ordm; counterclockwise to the closed position.</para>
<note><para>Request that flight deck select ENGINE BLEED Switch OFF
before proceeding to next step.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>After the flight crew switches engine bleed off, lock
the PRSOV in the locked closed position by depressing the manual override
drive approximately 1/4 inch.  Then turn the drive counter-clockwise
to the locked closed position (90&ordm; past the closed position).
Advise flight deck that the PRSOV is locked closed.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
