<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="31" chg="U" itemnbr="6" key="UPS747MEL20070815104045" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="61">
<title>EFIS/EICAS Interface Units (EIU)</title>
<dispcond category="B" maintenance="YES" nbrins="3" nbrreq="2"
operation="NO">
<remarks>
<para>Center or right EIU may be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>EIU Instrument Source Selector is verified to be operative,
and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>EICAS EIU Selector is verified to be operative.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815104046">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>EIU ___</para>
</note>
</operation>
<placard>
<para>Install appropriate Placard(s) in accordance with Dispatch Maintenance
Procedure. Enter item(s) in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815104047">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Deactivate the inoperative EIU by opening and collaring
the associated P7 panel EIU C or EIU R circuit breaker.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify EIU Instrument Source Selector is operative.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>On Captain&rsquo;s source select panel, position EIU
source selector to inoperative EIU and observe that Captain&rsquo;s
EFIS displays are blank. Select L on source selector and observe that
EFIS displays return to normal. Then select the other operative EIU
(C or R) on source selector and observe that EFIS displays are normal.
Return selector to AUTO position and observe that EFIS displays remain
normal.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Repeat procedure A on First Officer&rsquo;s source
select panel and EFIS displays.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If EIU selectors are positioned to the same source
on both pilots&rsquo; source selectors, the EICAS advisory message
SOURCE SEL EIU will be displayed. Captain&rsquo;s and First Officer&rsquo;s
instruments must be on separate sources for dispatch. See MEL <refint
refid="UPS747MEL20070815104451" reftype="MEL"> 34-00-1-1 </refint
> for dispatch with inoperative EIU auto-select feature.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>With AUTO selected on both pilots&rsquo; EIU source
selectors, check that EICAS advisory message SOURCE SEL EIU is not
displayed.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>On both pilots&rsquo; EIU source selectors, placard
selector position corresponding to inoperative EIU (C or R) &ldquo;INOP.&rdquo;</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify EICAS EIU selector is operative.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>With both primary and secondary EICAS displays operating,
position EICAS EIU selector to the inoperative EIU and observe that
EICAS displays are blank.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Position selector to L and observe that EICAS displays
return to normal. Then select the other operative EIU (C or R) on
selector and observe that EICAS displays are normal. Return selector
to AUTO and observe that EICAS display remains normal.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Placard selector position corresponding to inoperative
EIU (C or R) &ldquo;INOP.&rdquo;</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para><emphasis role="bold">If EICAS message EIU DISAGREE
is displayed while performing this maintenance procedure, dispatch
is not allowed.</emphasis></para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
