<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="24" chg="U" itemnbr="2-0-1" key="UPS747MEL20070815102515" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="21">
<title>APU Drive Generator Systems (Generator, AGCU, APB) &ndash;
(APB's) Remains Open </title>
<dispcond category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="2" nbrreq="0"
operation="NO" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided associated Auxiliary Power Breaker(s)
(APBs) remains open.</para>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815102516">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>APU GEN ___</para>
</note>
<note><para>When dispatching with APU Gen 1 inop turn #4 DEMAND PUMP
to AUTO for pushback, #4 AUX inop due to Gnd Handling bus not powered.</para>
</note>
<note><para>If EEC CLNG SUP FAN status message is displayed, it can
be cleared by rotating the EQUIP COOLING switch to OVRD, then back
to NORM.</para></note>
</operation>
<placard>
<para>Placard APU GEN Switch "INOP" and enter item in Aircraft Deferred
Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815102517">
<title>APU DRIVE GENERATOR SYSTEMS (GENERATOR, AGCU, APB)</title>
<para>Determine the APU Drive Generator System failure mode and accomplish
the following steps as applicable:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>APU Drive Generator Bearing Failure:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Check the EICAS for status message APU GEN BEARING
which indicates an APU generator bearing failure.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If a bearing failure has occurred, deactivate the
associated generator as follows:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Verify BATTERY switch, located on P5 overhead panel,
is set to ON.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify the associated APU generator FIELD OFF light
is illuminated on the P461 panel.</para>
<note><para>If the FIELD OFF light is extinguished, momentarily toggle
and release the associated APU generator field switch on the P461
panel.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Place INOP placard on appropriate APU GEN switch (P5
panel). </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Limit operation of the APU to ground use only (do
not use during takeoff).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Do not operate the APU in excess of 15 hours total
cumulative time following the initial bearing failure. Refer to item
49-11-1 to deactivate the APU if necessary.</para>
<note><para>The generator will be operating in a no-load condition
when the APU is operating. Operation of APU for more than 15 hours
total cumulative time following the initial generator bearing failure
may result in severe damage to the APU generator and APU.</para></note>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>APU Drive Generator Electrical Failure, Auxiliary
Generator Control Unit (AGCU) Failure:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Verify EICAS status message APU GEN BEARING is not
displayed. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If status message is present, refer to (M) step 1
&ldquo;APU Drive Generator Bearing Failure.&rdquo;</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If the messages are not present, deactivate the generator(s)
as follows:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Verify BATTERY switch, located on P5 overhead panel,
is set to ON.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify the associated APU generator FIELD OFF light
is illuminated on the P461 panel.</para>
<note><para>If the FIELD OFF light is extinguished, momentarily toggle
and release the associated APU generator field switch on the P461
panel.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Place INOP placard on appropriate APU GEN switch (P5
panel). </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>The generator will be operating in a no-load condition
when the APU is operating. In this configuration, the potential for
a generator bearing failure still exists. If the APU is operated,
verify EICAS status message APU GEN BEARING is not displayed before
each departure.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If status message is present, refer to step 1, &ldquo;APU
Driven Generator Bearing Failure.&rdquo;</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Auxiliary Power Breaker (APB) Failure:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Apply electrical power through external power receptacle
No. 1 or apply power from engine-driven generator No.1 and/or No.
2.</para>
<note><para>If electrical power (from either an external power source
or from engine-driven generator power) cannot be connected to the
aircraft, this is an indication auxiliary power breaker No. 1 is failed
closed.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify all BUS TIE switches, located on P5 overhead
panel, are set to AUTO.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that the ISLN lights, located on P5 overhead
panel, are extinguished.</para>
<note><para>If any ISLN lights are illuminated when engine generator
power is applied, this is an indication auxiliary power breaker (No.
1 and No. 2) is failed closed.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify split system breaker OPEN light, located on
P461 pilots&rsquo; overhead maintenance panel is extinguished.</para>
<note><para>If split system breaker light is illuminated, toggle SPLIT
SYSTEM BREAKER switch to close breaker. If split system breaker OPEN
light remains illuminated, this is an indication auxiliary power breaker
No. 2 is failed closed.</para></note>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
