<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="36" chg="U" itemnbr="4" key="UPS747MEL20070815104932" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="11">
<title>Wing Isolation Valves &ndash; (Left and Right)</title>
<dispcond category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="2" nbrreq="1"
operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>One may be inoperative deactivated open provided the pack on
the same side as operative valve is operative.</para>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815104933">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>BLEED ISLN ___</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>With a Wing Isolation Valve deactivated in the open
position the following Non-Normal procedures are modified. The new
procedures are located in the AOM Chapter 2.1 and QRH. Ensure that
the proper checklist for the deferred condition is used.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>SMOKE AIR CONDITIONING - the changes affect which
pack is turned off to isolate the smoke.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>BLEED DUCT LEAK L, C or R - the changes affect closing
engine bleed valves since one wing isolation valve is deactivated
open.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<placard>
<para>Placard adjacent to associated Wing Isolation Valve switch (overhead
panel): "L/R WING ISLN VALVE INOP OPEN". Enter item in Aircraft Deferred
Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815104934">
<para>The two isolation valves are installed in the pneumatic manifold
aft of the air-conditioning bay.  It is necessary to open the appropriate
air-conditioning access door to gain access to the valves.  To deactivate
the isolation valve, you must put the valve in the open position and
disconnect the electrical connector.</para>
<para>Deactivate the Wing Isolation Valve</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Supply electrical power (AMM 24-22-00/201).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open the access door 191NL for the left isolation
valve or 192NR for the right isolation valve (AMM 06-09-03/201).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Put the wing ISLN switch (P5 Overhead Panel) in the
open position.  Wait approximately 10 seconds for the valve to open.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open and collar the associated P6 panel L ISO VLV
AIR SUPPLY PWR or R ISO VLV AIR SUPPLY PWR circuit breaker.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Examine the position indicator on the actuator housing.
 If the position indicator is not in the OPEN position, turn the manual
drive until the valve is in the OPEN position.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Disconnect, cap and stow the electrical connector
from the isolation valve:</para><para>DV108 VALVE - WING ISOLATION
L</para>
<para>DV109 VALVE - WING ISOLATION R</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove electrical power if it is not necessary for
other operations (AMM 24-22-00/201).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the applicable access door (191NL or 192NR).</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
