<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="21" chg="U" itemnbr="1-2" key="UPS747MEL20070815101342" revdate="20100707" revnbr="8" sectnbr="31">
<title>Outflow Valves </title>
<dispcond category="C" maintenance="YES" nbrins="2" nbrreq="0"
operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Flight is conducted in an unpressurized configuration,</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Procedures are established and used to verify main
deck and lower lobe cargo compartments remain empty or contain only
empty cargo handling equipment, ballast (ballast may be loaded in
ULDs), or Fly Away Kits,</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Extended overwater flight is prohibited, and</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Crew rests, crew workstations and passenger business
centers with a door and smoke detection system (except the Combi Enlarged
Lav/Business Center) are empty, locked closed and placard INOPERATIVE
- DO NOT ENTER.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>UPS does not carry Fly Away Kits in voided cargo compartments.</para>
</note>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815101343">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>OUTFLOW VALVE ___</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>&Ensuretheloadsupervisor;</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>With supernumeraries on board, en&nbsp;route altitude
must be limited to 10,000 feet.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Equipment cooling may be operated in NORM or STBY.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If operation with Equipment Cooling in OVRD mode becomes
necessary inflight, an unpressurized configuration yields insufficient
equipment cooling.  Flight time must therefore be limited to 60 minutes
when in OVRD mode.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>A minimum of two pack operation is required for unpressurized
flight.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MEL20070815101344">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Flight will be unpressurized.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Flight is limited to an en&nbsp;route altitude of
10,000 feet with supernumeraries on board.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Main cargo deck and lower cargo holds remain empty,
or contain only empty cargo handling equipment.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Flight must be within 60 minutes of an suitable airport. </para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Extended overwater flight is prohibited.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Crew rests area is empty, and secured closed.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard associated Manual Outflow Valve "OUTFLOW VLVS INOP".
 Enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log. Placard the Upper Deck
Crew Rest - "COMPARTMENT INOPERATIVE - DO NOT ENTER".</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815101345">
<para><emphasis role="underline">BOTH OUTFLOW VALVES INOPERATIVE -
UNPRESSURIZED FLIGHT</emphasis></para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Deactivate both left and right outflow valves open
as detailed below:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Open and collar P6 panel CABIN PRESS CONT L ICU and
CABIN PRESS CONT R ICU circuit breakers.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open and collar P414 panel CABIN PRESS ICU LEFT and
CABIN PRESS ICU RIGHT circuit breakers.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Determine position of both outflow valves. If not
fully open, manually open by one of the following methods:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>If manual control is available:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Select outflow valves to manual control (MAN L or
MAN R ON), and drive valves fully open.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Deselect manual control (MAN L or MAN R OFF).</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If manual control is not available:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Remove AC motor from both outflow valves per (AMM
21-31-06/401).</para>
<note><para>Caution should be taken so as not to lose AC motor shim
plate.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open valves by applying torque to actuator output
shaft.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Reinstall AC motor.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Check that the upper Deck Crew Rest (Freighter) compartment
is empty, locked closed.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
