<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="32" chg="U" itemnbr="2" key="UPS747MEL20070815104317" revdate="20081208" revnbr="5a" sectnbr="53">
<title>Body Gear Steering Indication System</title>
<dispcond attr-rev="NO" category="C" downgrade="" maintenance="YES"
nbrins="1" nbrreq="0" operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>May be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Body gear steering actuators are verified locked,</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Body gear steering is deactivated, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Body gear steering actuator integrity is verified
before each departure.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815104318">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>BODY GR STRG SYS</para>
<para>> BODY GEAR STRG</para>
</note>
<note><para>On takeoff, assure all 4 engines are spooled evenly at
70% N1, prior to engaging TOGA.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>With the body gear steering deactivated or inoperative,
turning capability will be reduced. See the illustration in the AOM
chapter 3, for the depiction of the approximate minimum turning radius
using differential thrust in addition to nose wheel steering. As with
all turns, the cockpit must travel outside the centerline of the turn
to align the main path. The tip of the winglet describes the largest
arc while turning and determines the minimum obstruction clearance
path. All other portions of the aircraft structure are within this
arc. It should be noted from the turning radius illustration that
the wingtips are moved outboard about 11 feet, and travel 59 feet
in front of the cockpit.</para>
<caution><para>DO NOT ATTEMPT TO MAKE A TURN AWAY FROM AN OBSTACLE
WITHIN 11 FEET OF THE WINGTIP OR WITHIN 59 FEET OF THE COCKPIT.</para>
</caution>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Avoid sharp turns if possible, due to excessive tire
scrubbing. </para>
<caution><para>AVOID USE OF EXCESSIVE THRUST IN RAMP AREA DUE TO POSSIBLE
DAMAGE OR INJURY FROM JET WAKE.</para></caution>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Use modified GEAR LEVER WILL NOT MOVE UP Non-Normal
Procedure for Body Gear Steering deactivated in the AOM Chapter 2.1
and QRH.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MEL20070815104319">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Minimum 170 feet of pavement required for 180 degree
turn. </para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard Captain&rsquo;s PFD on P-1-1 panel: "BODY GEAR STRG
IND SYS INOP". Enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815104320">
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Logbook at the prescribed intervals.
(Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<note><para>The indication system is designed to display the EICAS
advisory message >BODY GEAR STRG and status message BODY GR STRG SYS
if the system is operating when not commanded. This requires that
both body gear steering actuator lock switches (primary and alternate)
indicate a body gear steering actuator is unlocked when the system
is not armed. A single lock switch failure is not annunciated on EICAS,
and does not constitute an inoperative indication system. </para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Verify that the body gear steering actuators are locked
using DMP <refint refid="UPS747MEL20070815104314" reftype="DMP"> 32-53-1</refint
> procedure 1.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Deactivate the body gear steering system using the
appropriate procedure(s) from DMP <refint refid="UPS747MEL20070815104314"
reftype="DMP"> 32-53-1</refint>.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Disconnect, cap and stow the electrical connector
on the affected body gear steering actuator(s).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Before each departure, verify actuator integrity using
DMP <refint refid="UPS747MEL20070815104314" reftype="DMP"> 32-53-1</refint
> procedure 1.B.1. through 1.B.3.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
