<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="78" chg="U" itemnbr="1-1" key="UPS747MEL20070815105646" revdate="20100707" revnbr="8" sectnbr="31">
<title>Thrust Reverser Systems and REV Unlock Indications</title>
<dispcond attr-rev="NO" category="C" downgrade="CATEGORY 3a"
maintenance="YES" nbrins="4" nbrreq="3" operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>One may be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Associated reverser is secured in the forward thrust
position, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>On associated engine, both T/R Control and T/R Indication
circuit breakers are opened and collared.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815105647">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>ENG ___ REVERSER</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Thrust Reversers are deactivated and cannot be used.
The REV amber indication may be displayed. Use Symmetrical reverse
as required.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>The thrust reverser deactivation will not affect control
of engine idle speed during flight but the affected engines will stay
in minimum idle on the ground. Therefore, EICAS message IDLE DISAGREE
may be annunciated during landing when the unaffected engines are
commanded to approach idle for reverse thrust operation.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MEL20070815105648">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Downgrade Aircraft Category Dispatch Status to CAT
3a.</para></numlitem>
<!--Per C.R.4299 David B. 12/16/2009 Rev 8-->
<numlitem><para>Takeoff on cluttered or icy runway is prohibited.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Placard below Captain&rsquo;s PFD on P-1-1 panel: "ENG ___ REVERSER
INOP". Enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815105649">
<para>Deferral of this item requires downgrading to the status indicated
in the A/C STATUS DISPATCH column below.</para>
<table>
<tgroup align="center" cols="3">
<colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.00*"/>
<colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.99*"/>
<colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.01*"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">INOP POSITION</emphasis></para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">NUMBER INOP</emphasis></para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">A/C STATUS DISPATCH</emphasis></para>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<para>&ndash;</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>1</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>CAT 3a</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Deactivate the associated Thrust Reverser:</para>
<warning><para>this deactivation procedure is mandated by faa airworthiness
directive 2000-17-06 and faa airworthiness directive 2003-16-16; this
procedure can not be changed unless directed by boeing, the faa and
ups powerplant engineering.</para></warning>
<warning><para>DEACTIVATION OF THE THRUST REVERSER SYSTEM WILL BE
PROPERLY ACCOMPLISHED WHEN ALL STEPS SHOWN IN THESE PROCEDURES ARE
FOLLOWED.  DEVIATIONS TO THESE PROCEDURES, OR CHANGING THE SYSTEM
CONFIGURATION, MAY RESULT IN IMPROPER DEACTIVATION AND UNCOMMANDED
DEPLOYMENT OF THE REVERSER.</para></warning>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Open, collar, and attach DO-NOT-CLOSE identifiers
to the P6 panel ENG START CONTROL circuit breaker and the following
circuit breakers for the associated engine:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Engine 1:  ENG 1 T/R IND and ENG 1 T/R CONT</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Engine 2:  ENG 2 T/R IND and ENG 2 T/R CONT</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Engine 3:  ENG 3 T/R IND and ENG 3 T/R CONT</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Engine 4:  ENG 4 T/R IND and ENG 4 T/R CONT</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Open the fan cowl panels (Ref AMM 71-11-04/201).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove the two bolts securing the lockout plate over
the lower CDU manual drive pad and remove the plate (two places).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Do the Thrust Reverser Electro-Mechanical Brake and
Flexshaft - Adjustment/Test procedure (Ref AMM 78-34-07/501).  Leave
fan cowls open upon completion of test.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Stow the thrust reverser halves (Ref AMM 78-31-00/201).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>(Optional procedure)  Remove one, two or three red
deactivation plates from the lower torque box of each reverser half.
 Install the plate(s) on the lock point(s) on each reverser half with
bolts (two bolts per deactivation plate).  It may be necessary to
drive the CDUs or the angle gearboxes at the manual drive pads to
align the holes in the brakes (if installed) must be manually released
to drive the CDUs or angle gearboxes (Ref AMM 78-31-00/201). </para>
<note><para>The Lock points are marked with the stencil LOCK POINTS.</para>
</note>
<note><para>The red deactivation plates are designed as lock out indicators;
they are not lock out retention devices.  Installation of at least
one plate is recommended, but not required.</para></note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>At both CDUs, install the lockout plate with the square
drive inserted into the manual drive pad.  Tighten bolts to 24-27
pound-inches. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>(FADEC)  Verify that thrust reverser position feedback
sensors (RVDTs) on both CDUs are properly installed and rigged as
follows:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Apply ground test power to EEC.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Verify that thrust reverser position (T/RR, T/RL,
Channels A and B) reads between -2% and +2% on the EICAS EPCS page.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If required, re-rig the RVDT (AMM 78-34-10/501).</para>
<caution><para>DO NOT DISCONNECT THE RVDT ELECTRICAL CONNECTOR FOR
DISPATCH.  A DISCONNECTED RVDT MAY RESULT IN UNCOMMANDED REDUCTION
OF THRUST IN FLIGHT. </para></caution>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Return the CDU brake release handles and, if installed,
the elctro-mechanical brake release handles to the normal, brake engaged
position (Ref AMM 78-31-00/201).</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Close the fan cowl panels (Ref. AMM 71-11-04/201).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove collar, remove DO-NOT-CLOSE identifier, and
close P6 panel ENG START CONTROL circuit breaker opened in step 1.
 The ENG_T/R IND and ENG_ T/R CONTR breakers associated with the deactivated
thrust reverser must remain opened and collared for dispatch.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Damaged or broken drag links must be removed per AMM
78-31-15.  Aluminum tape blocker doors shut.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
<graphic chapnbr="78" chg="U" key="UPS747MEL20070815105650"
revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="31">
<sheet chg="U" gnbr="747-400_DMP_CH_78_Page_3"
key="UPS747MEL20070815105651" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5"></sheet>
</graphic>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
