<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="32" chg="U" itemnbr="1" key="UPS747MEL20070815104052" revdate="20080827" revnbr="5" sectnbr="10">
<title>Main Gear Wheel Tiebolts</title>
<dispcond category="A" maintenance="YES" nbrins="288" nbrreq="272">
<remarks>
<para>One per wheel may be broken or missing provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Affected wheel is removed, checked for broken parts
or damage, and replaced if broken parts or damage is found,</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Associated brake is checked for broken parts or damage,
and is replaced or deactivated if broken parts or damage is found,</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>After each landing, wheel is inspected for additional
broken or missing tiebolts, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Operations are limited to five departures before repairs
are made.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<placard>
<para>Placard below Captain&rsquo;s PFD on P-1-1 panel: "WHEEL(S)___
TIEBOLT MISSING". Enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815104053">
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Logbook at the prescribed intervals.
(Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<para>Remove the wheel and tire assembly, and inspect the wheel and
brake assemblies for broken parts or damage. Inspect the wheel after
each landing and replace the affected wheel after five departures.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Deflate affected wheel to 40 psig or less.</para>
<caution><para>YOU MUST DEFLATE THE TIRE BEFORE YOU REMOVE THE WHEEL
AND TIRE ASSEMBLY. A DEFECTIVE WHEEL AND TIRE CAN BURST IF YOU DO
NOT DEFLATE THE TIRE BEFORE YOU REMOVE THE ASSEMBLY. INJURY TO PERSONS
OR DAMAGE TO EQUIPMENT CAN OCCUR.</para></caution>
<note><para>Do not move the aircraft while the tire is deflated. If
the aircraft is moved, the deflated tire and associated wheel, and
the wheel and tire on the opposite side of the axle must be replaced.</para>
</note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Remove each wheel with a broken, loose or missing
tiebolt per AMM 32-45-01/401.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Inspect the wheel for broken parts or damage.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If other bolts are broken, loose or missing, or if
other areas of the wheel have been damaged, the affected wheel is
to be replaced.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Inspect the brake for broken or missing parts or damage
(AMM 32-41-15/601). If parts are missing or damage is found, the affected
brake is to be replaced or deactivated (MEL item 32-41-1-X).</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Re-install the affected wheel per AMM 32-45-01/401.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Inflate tire to correct pressure per AMM 12-15-06/301.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>After each landing (up to 5 maximum), inspect remaining
tiebolts on the affected wheel (wheel removal not required) to ensure
no other bolts are broken, loose or missing. The affected wheel is
to be replaced immediately if discrepant tiebolts are found.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Replace the affected wheel after a <emphasis
role="underline">maximum</emphasis> of 5 subsequent landings.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
