<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE item PUBLIC "-//UPS//DTD MELCDL-REV1//EN" "melcdl.dtd">
<item chapnbr="32" chg="U" itemnbr="2" key="UPS747MEL20070815104213" revdate="20090824" revnbr="7" sectnbr="42">
<title>Alternate Anti-skid Valves</title>
<dispcond attr-rev="NO" category="C" downgrade="CATEGORY 3a"
maintenance="YES" nbrins="8" nbrreq="7" operation="YES" btb="YES">
<remarks>
<para>One valve (affecting two wheels) may be inoperative provided:</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Both of the associated brakes are deactivated by capping
the supply pressure hydraulic line, and</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>AOM/AA Data performance decrements are applied.</para>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</remarks>
<operation key="UPS747MEL20070815104214">
<note><para>The following EICAS message(s) may be displayed:</para>
<para>ANTI-SKID</para>
</note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Stopping distances will increase.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Leave gear down for a minimum of 2 minutes after takeoff
to permit affected wheel(s) to spin down prior to gear retraction.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Observe performance limitations.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Maximum takeoff thrust must be used.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
<note><para>At takeoff weights greater than 720,000 lbs., flaps up
maneuver speed (V<sub>REF</sub> + 100 kt) may exceed the landing gear
retract speed (270 kt). Therefore, ensure gear is retracted prior
to selecting Flaps Up.</para></note>
</operation>
<limitation key="UPS747MEL20070815104215">
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Downgrade Aircraft Category Dispatch Status to CAT
3a.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Compute V1 using the V1 correction, One or Two Brakes
Deactivated or One or Two Anti-Skid Channels Inoperative worksheet
in the AOM Chapter 5.1. </para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Apply takeoff performance runway weight corrections
from the Takeoff Runway Limit Weight Reduction, Landing Gear Extended
or Brake(s) Deactivated By Capping chart found in the AOM Chapter
5.1.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Apply restricted takeoff climb weights from the Takeoff
Climb Limit Weight, Landing Gear Extended or Brake(s) Deactivated
By Capping chart found in the AOM Chapter 5.1.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Apply landing weight performance for 1 or 2 brakes
deactivated in the AA landing data.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>If "Obstacle Clearance Altitude (OCA)" is present
on the AA Data for the departure runway, contact Flight Control for
alternate AA Data.</para></numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Operations on cluttered or icy runways prohibited.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Use cutback runway is prohibited.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</limitation>
<placard>
<para>Install Placards as directed in DMP procedure. Enter item in
Aircraft Deferred Item Log.</para>
</placard>
<maintenance key="UPS747MEL20070815104216">
<note><para>The repetitive inspection required when this item is inoperative
must be documented in the Aircraft Logbook at the prescribed intervals.
(Refer to GMM, Chapter 3, Section 6.)</para></note>
<para>Deferral of this item requires downgrading to the status indicated
in the A/C STATUS DISPATCH column below.</para>
<table>
<tgroup align="center" cols="3">
<colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.00*"/>
<colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.03*"/>
<colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.97*"/>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">INOP POSITION</emphasis></para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">NUMBER INOP</emphasis></para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para><emphasis role="bold">A/C STATUS DISPATCH</emphasis></para>
</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>
<para>&ndash;</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>1</para>
</entry>
<entry>
<para>CAT 3a</para>
</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<para>Placard Captain&rsquo;s PFD on P-1-1 panel: "WHEEL_ BRAKE(S)
DEACTIVATED WITH LINES CAPPED". Enter item in Aircraft Deferred Item
Log.</para>
<para>Cap and deactivate the associated brake lines and prior to every
flight review CMC messages when ANTISKID advisory message is displayed.</para>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Deactivate the associated brakes using DMP 32-41-1-2.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For ANTISKID advisory message displayed, before each
flight review CMC for additional antiskid faults.</para>
<note><para>The ground set-up procedure may be simplified. The IRUs
do not need to be in NAV mode. (Ignore any IRS signal fault indications).
Hydraulic pressure is not required. Autobrake system does not need
to be armed.</para></note>
<numlist>
<numlitem><para>Select 32 BRAKE CONTROL from the CMC GROUND TEST menu.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Execute the BRAKE SYSTEM BITE test. Record all antiskid
system configuration and input faults annunciated during the test.</para>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>Following the conclusion of the CMC Brake System Ground
Test, select the line-select key opposite the FAIL prompt on the CMC
and record the antiskid system fault. Continue to select the NEXT
PAGE key on the CMC as required and record the antiskid system faults.</para>
<note><para> When CMC message PARK BRK VLV NOT OPEN WHEN RELEASED
or NO PARK BRKE PWR is displayed, dispatch is not allowed (Brake Torque
Limiter is inoperative). This condition causes Status message PARK
BRK VALVE as well as ANTISKID OFF and BRAKE LIMITER Advisory messages.</para>
</note>
</numlitem>
<numlitem><para>For additional faults indicated, use DMP item 32-42-1-0-1,
32-42-1-1, 32-42-1-1-1, or 32-42-1-2 as applicable.</para></numlitem>
</numlist>
</numlitem>
</numlist>
</maintenance>
</dispcond>
</item>
